<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sheeny Care</title>
    <description>Skin Care is made easy with Sheeny Care as we help you make skincare routines understand skincare products, talk about various skin care regimen, and give you insights on beauty products and services.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 15:25:59 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 15:25:59 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Retinol and How Can You Use it in Skin Care Routine?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinol was one of those ingredients that I incorporated into my skincare routine as soon as I completed my research on it. The fact that retinol is considered equivalent to the gold standard in skincare products tells a lot about the volume of it and the advantages it has over the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, retinol is one of the most studied skincare ingredients and today we can find several products with retinol in them such as retinol creams and retinol serums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a key ingredient that is used today to improve the skin. To be precise, retinol deals with fine lines, wrinkles, pore size, uneven skin tone, and texture. It is also proven to treat acne. It indeed is an ingredient with superpowers, so let’s get heads on about it more in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-retinol&quot;&gt;What is Retinol?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retinol is a form of vitamin A, a fat-soluble derivative. It is mostly found in animal foods such as whole milk, oily fish, and liver. It promotes skin cell turnover and helps your body form and maintain healthy skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, it is a type of retinoid of which there are several variations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retinoic acid&lt;/strong&gt; - It is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms/def/bioavailable&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bioavailable&lt;/a&gt; and works faster than other variations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retinol/Retinaldehyde/Esters&lt;/strong&gt; - These need to be converted by your skin into retinoic acid and hence works slower than other variations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, there are several types of retinol with a variety of percentages and ingredient subtypes. There is a weird kind of myth about retinol which says &lt;strong&gt;All retinol is the same&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retinol is a huge family of the compound derivative of vitamin A. It goes from &lt;strong&gt;Over the Counter (OTC)&lt;/strong&gt; to prescription strength in topical and oral medication form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-we-get-vitamin-c-from-foods&quot;&gt;How do we get Vitamin C from foods?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several good sources of vitamin C in foods. We get vitamin C from several foods such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citrus fruits like Oranges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strawberry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackcurrants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brussels sprouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potatoes etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we’re probably getting Vitamin C from our diet we do not know whether it does go into our skin or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;forms-of-vitamin-c-in-skin-care&quot;&gt;Forms of Vitamin C in Skin Care&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-ascorbic acid is the purest and potent form of Vitamin C. It is one of the most important and commonly used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredient&lt;/a&gt; as it has a huge role in collagen synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other less potent derivatives of L-ascorbic acid are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sodium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Palmitate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Glucoside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-O Ethyl Ascorbic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all the forms of Vitamin C have antioxidants, there are few formulas of vitamin C that works better than the other in skin care.
As said earlier, Ascorbic Acid, also known as the L-Ascorbic acid is the most studied form of vitamin C. When this formula is properly created below the pH level of 4(2.6 - 3.2) which is the ideal range, it helps create younger looking, firmir skin while fading dark spots, pigmentations and signs of uneven skin tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are studies of Vitamin C with higher concerntration of upto 30% and have been used in the study of animal, maximum absorbtion was found with a 20% Vitamin C solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve known that Vitamin C a highly beneficial antioxidant ingredient, it has plenty of other properties that helps both the skin and the body and deserves a permanent place in your skin care cabinets. Lets talk in depth about all the goodness of Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-it-suits-all-skin-type&quot;&gt;1. It suits all skin type:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is known to improve several skin issues but it is not limited to a skin type. Most people can easily use topical Vitamin C for a prolonged period of time, without having faced any reactions on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with hypersensitive skin may experience irritation but perhaps this occurs in rare cases only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-it-hydrates-the-skin&quot;&gt;2. It hydrates the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our skin is not properly hydrated in most of the cases. The reason behind this is very simple, we are top to bottom covered by the skin. Comprising 64% of water, your skin needs hydration.
Hence, one of the main vitamin C derivatives used in skin care called Magnesium ascorbyl phosphate, has been shown to help the skin retain water and prevent it from being too dry(dehydrated) or oily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-it-brightens-the-skin&quot;&gt;3. It brightens the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C helps fade pigmentation and reduce dullness of the skin, giving the skin a even tone and youthful glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-it-helps-lighten-pigmentation&quot;&gt;4. It helps lighten pigmentation:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperpigmentaion (sun-spots, age-spots and melasma) occurs when an enzyme called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/what-is-melanin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;melanin is over produced in the skin. Hypepigmentaion can also occured in areas where acne has healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C has shown to reduce the production of melanin in the skin and help fade dark spots leading to an even tone skin complexion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5-it-promotes-collagen-production&quot;&gt;5. It promotes collagen production:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collagen is a naturally occuring protein that depletes over time. Vitamin C is well known for boosting collagen production in the skin. Lower level of collagen leads to fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase in collagen production has multiple advantages to the skin. This protein helps give skin that tight and plump look. Regular use of Vitamin C will slow down skin aging as it keeps producing enough collagen in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-it-lessens-the-appearance-of-fine-lines-and-wrinkles&quot;&gt;6. It lessens the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C protects the skin against any damages and help skin to regenerate. With additional hydration benefits and collagen stimulation, our skin neutralizes free radicals. Thus, lessening the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7-it-revitalizes-sun-damaged-skin&quot;&gt;7. It revitalizes sun damaged skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over exposure of the skin to the sun has an adverse effect itself. We can observe skin issues such as flakiness, discolored patches (sunspots), rough areas, rosacea, etc. The damages by the sun are due to a molecule called free radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are atoms but with missing elctrones. Hence, on their serach of electon, they steat it from our skin, causing a significant damage to the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Vitamin C is rich in antioxidant and they protect the skin cells by giving an electron to these radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;8-it-helps-soothe-sunburns&quot;&gt;8. It helps soothe sunburns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of sunscreen is doubled when Vitamin C is layered underneath it. Hence, Vitamin C aids in calming the skin and increasing the cell turnover. Hence, the sunburnt skin is rejuvenated faster i.e it replaces the damaged cells with healthy new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Who needs Vitamin C Serum?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skin type&lt;/strong&gt; needs Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C can be used both in the AM and PM after cleansing the skin. Furthermore, it can also be layered with acids and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;niacinamide&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it can be irritating if used in a high percentage. Hence, if you are new to this ingredient, opt for a less potent derivative or lower percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stability-of-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Stability of Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stability of this ingredient depends on its formulation, preservatives used, and encapsulation. The reason behind this is because ascorbic acid easily oxidizes to dehydroascorbic acid when exposed to oxygen &amp;amp; light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily determine whether the product you have has oxidized or not by checking its color. If the color of the serum tends to be brown or orange from colorless, then it probably has been oxidized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxidized vitamin c is likely to be less effective to the skin. In other words, formulas with water are stabilized using Ferulic Acid and Vitamin E to slow down the oxidization process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Vitamin C starts working within &lt;strong&gt;6 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat &lt;strong&gt;hyperpigmentation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;hydrate the skin&lt;/strong&gt; whereas &lt;strong&gt;12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat &lt;strong&gt;fine lines and wrinkles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Vitamin C.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indeedlabs.com/shop/vitamin-c24-s/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Indeed Labs Vitamin C24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/ceo-vitamin-c-brightening-serum&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley C.E.O 15% Vitamin C Brightening Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-magnesium-ascorbyl-phosphate-10pct-30ml?redir=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate 10%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know you’re favourite serum if you have any and tell us why you love them so much. And if it’s Vitamin C, let’s discuss more on our favorite serum. Shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-retinol/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-retinol/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Salicylic Acid and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Salicylic Acid(SA) are a part of beta-hydroxy acid. BHA’s specifically are acne-treating ingredients. Most of the skincare product that deals with acne and breakouts contain salicylic acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is oil soluble and is known to remove dead skin cells by penetrating into the skin to reduce the sebum production .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it is a non-comedogenic ingredient, it is more likely to loosen blackheads and clear pores. Also, it is not irritating to your skin as compared to benzoyl peroxide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-sa&quot;&gt;Who needs SA?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acne-prone skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oily skin with closed comodones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackheads/Whiteheads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosacea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keratosis Piliaris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milia and Ingrown Hairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-sa&quot;&gt;How to use SA?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be used by directly applying into the affected areas. It is supposed to be applied after cleansing and toning. You can apply products with SA both in the AM as well as PM. You need to avoid the areas around your eyes to prevent any casualty that can arise due to this ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is known to reduce sebum secretion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It exfoliates the skin and unclogs the pores.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It sheds dead skin cells and debris.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is an anti-inflamatory and anti-bacterial skin care ingredient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It also offers a UV protective effect therefore does not make the skin sensitive to the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Salicylic Acid starts working within &lt;strong&gt;2 to 12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat &lt;strong&gt;acne&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, this ingredient is best for oily skin with comodones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paulaschoice.com/skin-perfecting-2pct-bha-liquid-exfoliant/201.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paula Choice 2% BHA Liquid Exfoliant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/ufo-acne-treatment-face-oil&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley U.F.O.
Ultra-Clarifying Acne Treatment Face Oil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-salicylic-acid-2pct-solution-30ml?redir=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Salicylic 2% Solution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-using-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip Using Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If used with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide:&lt;/a&gt; Salicylic Acid helps treat acne way sooner than you might have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-salicylic-acid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-salicylic-acid/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Vitamin C and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;What is Vitamin C?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the skin care game, then you have likely heard about Vitamin C serums. Most of the skin care enthusiast and dermatologists recommend
the use of vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C, also known as ascorbic acid and ascorbate, is a vitamin found in various foods and sold as a dietary supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a vital molecule for skin health. It is an essential nutrient found in high levels in both the dermis &amp;amp; epidermis. However, it depletes as we age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-we-get-vitamin-c-from-foods&quot;&gt;How do we get Vitamin C from foods?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several good sources of vitamin C in foods. We get vitamin C from several foods such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citrus fruits like Oranges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strawberry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackcurrants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brussels sprouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potatoes etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we’re probably getting Vitamin C from our diet we do not know whether it does go into our skin or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;forms-of-vitamin-c-in-skin-care&quot;&gt;Forms of Vitamin C in Skin Care&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-ascorbic acid is the purest and potent form of Vitamin C. It is one of the most important and commonly used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredient&lt;/a&gt; as it has a huge role in collagen synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other less potent derivatives of L-ascorbic acid are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sodium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Palmitate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Glucoside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-O Ethyl Ascorbic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all the forms of Vitamin C have antioxidants, there are few formulas of vitamin C that works better than the other in skin care.
As said earlier, Ascorbic Acid, also known as the L-Ascorbic acid is the most studied form of vitamin C. When this formula is properly created below the pH level of 4(2.6 - 3.2) which is the ideal range, it helps create younger looking, firmir skin while fading dark spots, pigmentations and signs of uneven skin tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are studies of Vitamin C with higher concerntration of upto 30% and have been used in the study of animal, maximum absorbtion was found with a 20% Vitamin C solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve known that Vitamin C a highly beneficial antioxidant ingredient, it has plenty of other properties that helps both the skin and the body and deserves a permanent place in your skin care cabinets. Lets talk in depth about all the goodness of Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-it-suits-all-skin-type&quot;&gt;1. It suits all skin type:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is known to improve several skin issues but it is not limited to a skin type. Most people can easily use topical Vitamin C for a prolonged period of time, without having faced any reactions on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with hypersensitive skin may experience irritation but perhaps this occurs in rare cases only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-it-hydrates-the-skin&quot;&gt;2. It hydrates the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our skin is not properly hydrated in most of the cases. The reason behind this is very simple, we are top to bottom covered by the skin. Comprising 64% of water, your skin needs hydration.
Hence, one of the main vitamin C derivatives used in skin care called Magnesium ascorbyl phosphate, has been shown to help the skin retain water and prevent it from being too dry(dehydrated) or oily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-it-brightens-the-skin&quot;&gt;3. It brightens the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C helps fade pigmentation and reduce dullness of the skin, giving the skin a even tone and youthful glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-it-helps-lighten-pigmentation&quot;&gt;4. It helps lighten pigmentation:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperpigmentaion (sun-spots, age-spots and melasma) occurs when an enzyme called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/what-is-melanin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;melanin is over produced in the skin. Hypepigmentaion can also occured in areas where acne has healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C has shown to reduce the production of melanin in the skin and help fade dark spots leading to an even tone skin complexion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5-it-promotes-collagen-production&quot;&gt;5. It promotes collagen production:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collagen is a naturally occuring protein that depletes over time. Vitamin C is well known for boosting collagen production in the skin. Lower level of collagen leads to fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase in collagen production has multiple advantages to the skin. This protein helps give skin that tight and plump look. Regular use of Vitamin C will slow down skin aging as it keeps producing enough collagen in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-it-lessens-the-appearance-of-fine-lines-and-wrinkles&quot;&gt;6. It lessens the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C protects the skin against any damages and help skin to regenerate. With additional hydration benefits and collagen stimulation, our skin neutralizes free radicals. Thus, lessening the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7-it-revitalizes-sun-damaged-skin&quot;&gt;7. It revitalizes sun damaged skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over exposure of the skin to the sun has an adverse effect itself. We can observe skin issues such as flakiness, discolored patches (sunspots), rough areas, rosacea, etc. The damages by the sun are due to a molecule called free radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are atoms but with missing elctrones. Hence, on their serach of electon, they steat it from our skin, causing a significant damage to the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Vitamin C is rich in antioxidant and they protect the skin cells by giving an electron to these radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;8-it-helps-soothe-sunburns&quot;&gt;8. It helps soothe sunburns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of sunscreen is doubled when Vitamin C is layered underneath it. Hence, Vitamin C aids in calming the skin and increasing the cell turnover. Hence, the sunburnt skin is rejuvenated faster i.e it replaces the damaged cells with healthy new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Who needs Vitamin C Serum?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skin type&lt;/strong&gt; needs Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C can be used both in the AM and PM after cleansing the skin. Furthermore, it can also be layered with acids and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;niacinamide&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it can be irritating if used in a high percentage. Hence, if you are new to this ingredient, opt for a less potent derivative or lower percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stability-of-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Stability of Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stability of this ingredient depends on its formulation, preservatives used, and encapsulation. The reason behind this is because ascorbic acid easily oxidizes to dehydroascorbic acid when exposed to oxygen &amp;amp; light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily determine whether the product you have has oxidized or not by checking its color. If the color of the serum tends to be brown or orange from colorless, then it probably has been oxidized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxidized vitamin c is likely to be less effective to the skin. In other words, formulas with water are stabilized using Ferulic Acid and Vitamin E to slow down the oxidization process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Vitamin C starts working within &lt;strong&gt;6 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat &lt;strong&gt;hyperpigmentation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;hydrate the skin&lt;/strong&gt; whereas &lt;strong&gt;12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat &lt;strong&gt;fine lines and wrinkles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Vitamin C.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indeedlabs.com/shop/vitamin-c24-s/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Indeed Labs Vitamin C24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/ceo-vitamin-c-brightening-serum&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley C.E.O 15% Vitamin C Brightening Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-magnesium-ascorbyl-phosphate-10pct-30ml?redir=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate 10%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know you’re favourite serum if you have any and tell us why you love them so much. And if it’s Vitamin C, let’s discuss more on our favorite serum. Shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are Niacinamide and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide reduces the apperance of skin blemishes and improves the skin barrier. It visibly minimizes pores and decreases infamation when used regularly in skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;bih=942&amp;amp;biw=1848&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk00oSvPZ9h3bCaV_WRgqhL0kwKE69Q%3A1600850648732&amp;amp;ei=2AprX8OQLLOS4-EP3vKbqAo&amp;amp;q=Nicotinamide&amp;amp;oq=Nicotinamide&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQR1DTnWhY051oYOCfaGgAcAN4AIABAIgBAJIBAJgBAKABAqABAaoBB2d3cy13aXrIAQjAAQE&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD3IWy8f7rAhUzyTgGHV75BqUQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nicotinamide&lt;/a&gt;, is one of two major forms of vitamin B3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;bih=942&amp;amp;biw=1848&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk00BSkNZYqrd-Gmm61tmlOL10wBaJw%3A1600852358375&amp;amp;ei=hhFrX_m4FpzB3LUPssKsiAY&amp;amp;q=niacin&amp;amp;oq=niacin&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQRzIECAAQR1DahgRY2oYEYMeIBGgAcAN4AIABAIgBAJIBAJgBAKABAqABAaoBB2d3cy13aXrIAQjAAQE&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwj5k6Lh9_7rAhWcILcAHTIhC2EQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(niacin)&lt;/a&gt; found in supplements. Today, it has been a promised &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredient&lt;/a&gt; to help manage acne, rosacea, pigmentation issues, and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-it&quot;&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, it is a form of vitamin B3. It is water soluble and unlike &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ceramide&lt;/a&gt;, our body doesn’t store it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-it&quot;&gt;Who needs it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skin type&lt;/strong&gt; needs niacinamide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-it&quot;&gt;Benefits of using it.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basically, niacinamide stimulates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ceramide&lt;/a&gt; and keratin production. Thus, improving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;bih=942&amp;amp;biw=1848&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk00-9atHnRd0QgSnl09g0SmLyMlyiw%3A1600852426468&amp;amp;ei=yhFrX82XHPGLmgeW7ragCA&amp;amp;q=skin+barrier&amp;amp;oq=skin+barrier&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzICCAAyAggAMgIIADICCAAyAggAMgIIADICCAAyAggAMgIIADICCAA6BAgAEEc6BAgAEEM6DgguELEDEIMBEMcBEK8BOggIABCxAxCDAToOCC4QsQMQgwEQxwEQowI6BAgjECc6BQgAEJECOgUIABCxAzoICC4QxwEQowI6BAgAEApQhbx6WLHKemD5y3poAHADeACAAf0BiAHaEZIBBTAuOC40mAEAoAEBqgEHZ3dzLXdpesgBCMABAQ&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjNpN6B-P7rAhXxheYKHRa3DYQQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skin barrier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It visibly minimizes pores and decreases inflamation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It reduces discolouration and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/ordinary-skin-care-routine-hyperpigmented-skin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hyperpigmentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It helps reduce the visibility of fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Niacinamide.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/moisturizers/pm-facial-moisturizing-lotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe PM Facial Moisturizing Lotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/niacinamide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Inkey List Niacinamide Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-niacinamide-10pct-zinc-1pct-30ml?ccvis=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ordinary Niacinamide 10% + Zinc 1%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Niacinamide starts working within &lt;strong&gt;4 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat hyperpigmentaion, redness and hydrate the skin whereas, &lt;strong&gt;8 to 12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat acne, fine lines and wrinkles. Furthermore, it takes upto &lt;strong&gt;2 to 6 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to reduce oiliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-it-the-talk-of-the-town&quot;&gt;Why is it the talk of the town?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common skin issues people have to face are acne,rosacea, pigmentation, fine lines and wrinkles. There are many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; that target such skin issues. However, Niacinamide is claimed to be the &lt;strong&gt;“active ingredient”&lt;/strong&gt; that targets all the skin issues at once and treat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the studies about it have been carried out at concentrations of 5% or below. And yes, it can do everything it’s purported to: improve hyperpigmentation, fortify barrier function, normalize sebum production etc. However, we need to realize that niacinamide, and a whole host of other “actives” can do more harm than good when overused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-niacinamide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-niacinamide/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are Ceramides and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ceramides are a skin barrier or protective layer that is present naturally in our skin. It is a part of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;hs=wcf&amp;amp;channel=fs&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk01vOXP40qPHjQ8BGTlRU17Llbb6Cg%3A1600836946253&amp;amp;ei=UtVqX_6LD82a4-EPqcqh2Ao&amp;amp;q=lipid+matrix&amp;amp;oq=lipid+matrix&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzICCAAyAggAMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjIGCAAQFhAeMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjIGCAAQFhAeMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjoECAAQRzoECAAQQzoFCC4QsQM6BQgAELEDOggIABCxAxCDAToECCMQJzoECC4QJzoCCC46BQgAEJECOgQIABAKUIalxgFY1rTGAWCUt8YBaABwAngAgAGLAogBjBWSAQQyLTEymAEAoAEBqgEHZ3dzLXdpesgBCMABAQ&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwj-_Jisvv7rAhVNzTgGHSllCKsQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lipid matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of our skin. Without the proper ratio of ceramides in our skin, it could result in dryness, itching and irritation. Therefore, compromising the skin barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, Ceramides are lipids that help form the skin’s barrier and help skin retain moisture. Ceramides also help the skin protect against environmental hazards like irritants and pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-it&quot;&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceramide naturally makes 50% of your skin. It is a long chain of lipids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you came across the word &lt;strong&gt;“lipid matrix”&lt;/strong&gt; in the article, let me tell you what it is. Ceramides forms lipid matrix in the skin.. This matrix is very flexible and creates a waterproof barrier in the skin i.e. it keeps the irritants our and water inside of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-it&quot;&gt;Who needs it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two skin types that need it the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/dry-skin-causes-and-treatment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensitive Skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceramide are one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; that is used to treat dry and sensitive skin. Hence, this ingredient is found in barrier repair creams and moisturisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-ceramides&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Ceramides.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basically, cereamides are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?channel=fs&amp;amp;client=ubuntu&amp;amp;q=emollient&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;emollient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, it hydrates the skin by forming a protective barrier, which reduces the water loss from the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It repairs the skin barrier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It makes the skin soft and sheeny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It helps improve the texture of the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;it has no SIDE EFFECTS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-ceramides&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Ceramides.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/moisturizers/pm-facial-moisturizing-lotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe PM Facial Moisturizing Lotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firstaidbeauty.com/skin-care-products/moisturizers/ultra-repair-cream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laroche-posay.us/face-and-body-skin-care/face-products/face-moisturizer/toleriane-double-repair-face-moisturizer-3337875545792.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-ceramide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-ceramide/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hyaluronic acid, everything you need to know, uses and skin benefits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a skin enthusiast you must have heard or read somewhere about this magical substance named Hyaluronic Acid! Putting it simply, Hyaluronic acid is the key to instantly plumping fine lines and making skin look all glowy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be found in everything from serums to sheet masks, but what exactly is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some insights to Hyaluronic Acid including the right way to incorporate it into your skincare routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-hyaluronic-acid&quot;&gt;What is Hyaluronic Acid?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid (HA) is actually a sugar present naturally in our skin that holds water and helps keep it hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hyaluronic Acid within our bodies holds a thousand times its weight in water. It retains all that moisture in our skin and joints. It also prevents all that moisture from evaporating into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, right? Just like collagen and elastin, the amount of naturally-occurring hyaluronic acid in our bodies decreases as we get older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, however, ways to help stimulate the production of HA in our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balanced Diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Antioxidants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hyaluronic-acid-is-a-super-humectant&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid is a Super Humectant!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid brings moisture to the surface of your skin when used in skin care products like creams and serums.
It can be used as a humectant in your skincare routine because of its ability to hold water. Hence, it continually keeps the skin moisturized throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pairing-ha-with-other-ingredients&quot;&gt;Pairing HA with other Ingredients!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid plays well with most other ingredients and is great while pairing with chemical peels, retinol, vitamins, and other acids.
The only exception would be acids with low pH levels, like glycolic acid. It may pollute the HA and make it ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;picking-up-right-ha&quot;&gt;Picking up right HA!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking the right hyaluronic acid product is really tricky. The molecule is often times too large to effectively deliver hydration deep into skin layers.
The molecule is micronized i.e. it penetrates the skin in order to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you are just putting it on top of the skin without it being helpful, obviously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-ha-injectable&quot;&gt;Is HA Injectable?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me everyone is skeptical about injecting anything on their body. With a few pricks of a needle, the gel plumps sunken areas, smooths fine lines, and decreases shadows. Then, slowly the gel dissolves over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fillers, HA is bound in a gel carrier that holds it in place where it is in use as an injection. The hyaluronic acid creates volume because it draws in water to the area, creating a filling effect. Still skeptical?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side effects&lt;/strong&gt; are minimal: you may experience some swelling or bruising that can last for two or three days. The most important thing to remember when getting any kind of filler or injectable. Please go to a trained and board-certified dermatologist or plastic surgeon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-ha-everyones-favorite&quot;&gt;Why is HA everyone’s favorite?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid is something our bodies already produce, it’s considered to be safe for use in all types of injectables.
Take the liquid nose job, for example, dermatologists use filler to even out bumps in the nose and improve the shape, or even to improve foot pain in patients who have lost the cushioning in their heels. It can be injected into the feet to improve the padding on the bone and decrease pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic Acid has many benefits for your skin! For all skin types. If you want to learn about the magical stuff it does, you should definitely check-up with your near and dear Dermatologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser - Everything You Need to Know, Uses and Ingredients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to really exfoliate with physical exfoliators…tsk tsk, I know right, I didn’t have the access to the right information like you guys do now &lt;em&gt;wink&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some research, I found out about our elixir, Salicylic Acid! Fantastically, infused in  CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser. As a result, I haven’t been turning back ever since. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salicylic Acid also improves dryness and softens the rough skin, we should really appreciate it &lt;em&gt;salutes&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product we really vouch for is by CeraVe, CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser infused with salicylic acid enhances the barrier-strengthening with the ingredients like ceramides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-should-we-use-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;Why Should We Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/cleansers/renewing-sa-cleanser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salicylic acid exfoliates for soft, smooth skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enriched with vitamin D for antioxidant protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bye-bye, dead skin cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser provides gentle, non-irritating exfoliation without harsh micro-beads or grains that can scratch or injure the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it is suitable for the face and body as well as acne-prone and psoriasis-prone skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The salicylic acid cleanser does more than just exfoliate the skin. It softens and helps to restore the skin’s natural barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-of-the-important-ingredients-in-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;Some of the important ingredients in CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ceramides:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps the skin retain moisture
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps repair a compromised skin barrier 
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-salicylic-acid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Salicylic Acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; deep cleanses the skin by penetrating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;How to CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firstly, wet skin with lukewarm water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secondly, massage the cleanser into the skin in a gentle, circular motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, rinse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser’s formula is also non-comedogenic, fragrance-free, and enriched with vitamin D for extra antioxidant protection. It effectively removes dirt, oil, and makeup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love their formula and the ingredients. As a result, the product is much loved in the beauty community. I’m going to get my bottle of CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser today, when are you going?  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cerave-salicylic-acid-cleanser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cerave-salicylic-acid-cleanser/</guid>
        
        <category>Face</category>
        
        <category>Cleanser</category>
        
        <category>CeraVe</category>
        
        <category>Acne-Prone Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser - Everything You Need to Know, Uses and Ingredients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have all seen and heard how dermatologists recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/cleansers/foaming-facial-cleanser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser&lt;/a&gt; for people with acne. It works to cleanse the skin and remove oil, without disrupting the skin’s protective barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it won’t clog pores or dry the skin out. The product contains niacin-amide (helps in dealing inflammation) and ceramides to help calm and moisturize irritated skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dermatologists believe that foaming facial cleanser is an ideal product for removing excess oil, dirt, and makeup. So, it’s really important to choose a formula that won’t do wrong to the skin’s natural protective barrier. Hence, CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser is really safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also beneficial to choose a gentle cleanser with ingredients that help maintain hydration to your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-of-the-important-ingredients&quot;&gt;Some of the important ingredients:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ceramides:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps the skin retain moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps repair a compromised skin barrier &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firstly, wet the skin with lukewarm water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secondly, massage the cleanser into the skin in a gentle, circular motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the end, just rinse it out and pat your face with a dry towel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser has been created with ceramides, hyaluronic acid, and niacin-amide. The products that focus on the skin’s barrier, attract hydration, and heal the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser deeply cleanses, removes excess oil, and refreshes the skin. Certainly, without over-stripping it or leaving it feeling tight and dry. Amazing, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I love their formula and ingredients. As a result, the product is much loved in the beauty community. They are non-comedogenic, non-irritating, and fragrance-free. The product is more suitable for normal to oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gel-based foaming cleanser is definitely an effective way to start off any skincare regimen for normal to oily skin. So, get your own CeraVe Foaming Facial Cleanser, right now! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cerave-foaming-facial-cleanser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cerave-foaming-facial-cleanser/</guid>
        
        <category>Face</category>
        
        <category>Cleanser</category>
        
        <category>CeraVe</category>
        
        <category>Oily Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Perfect Skin Care Routine for Oily Skin</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-insight-to-dry-skin&quot;&gt;An insight To &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/dry-skin-causes-and-treatment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medically known as Xerosis, dry skin is not usually serious and is caused by the temperature and humidity level around you. If you have dry skin, you might notice small fine flakes, cracking and dry patches in your skin. You should protect your skin in the morning and hydrate it in the evening that is why, you need to have a proper skin care routine for dry skin Hence, the skin condition could get worst if you do not add a skin care routine for your dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-routine-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Skin care routine for Dry Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hydrating-cleanser&quot;&gt;Hydrating Cleanser:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a very gentle but hydrating cleanser for about a minute to cleanse your skin.
Something as gentle as the &lt;u&gt;Himalaya moisturizing aloe vera face wash&lt;/u&gt; is a blessing to your skin. And if you would want to steep a little high, opt for a &lt;u&gt;cetaphil gentle skin cleanser&lt;/u&gt;. Just make sure the product you’re using doesn’t let your skin feel tight and stripping after the wash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;CeraVe's Hydrating Facial Cleanser&lt;/u&gt;, which includes ceramides and hyaluronic acid, has been internationally renowned today and seems to be the favorite cleanser for all. And for those who suffer from the redness, consider products with niacinamide as it aids with inflammation. A lot of people use these products in their skin care routine today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleansing Tip for extremely dry skin:&lt;/strong&gt;
Skip using a cleanser and just wash your face with normal water(not too cold, not too hot) to wash your face in the morning. Avoid foaming cleansers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hydrating-toner&quot;&gt;Hydrating Toner:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go easy with toners if you have sensitive skin. because most toners are full of alcohol and unwanted chemicals that are likely to harm your skin. I personally recommend using a gentle toner in your skin that is packed with good hydrating ingredients such as Hyaluronic Acid that would lock up all the moisture in your skin. If serums seem to exceed your budget, opt for a toner with hyaluronic acid.
&lt;u&gt;Neutrogena's Alcohol-Free Hydrating Toner&lt;/u&gt; can be your best pick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toning Tip for dry skin:&lt;/strong&gt;
Skip this step if the ingredient list on the toner you’re using seems to do nothing at all. Also, stop spending your money on Mario Badescu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;serum&quot;&gt;Serum:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serums are packed with concentrated ingredients. You have to choose an antioxidant protection serum such as Vitamin C in your skin care regimen, especially in the morning, . Vitamin C does wonders for your skin. Vitamin C serum from &lt;u&gt;DermaFix&lt;/u&gt; aids your skin beautifully despite a slight fragrance in it. But the ingredient list completely satisfies why it does have fragrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the night, a serum with retinol is a good option. “Retinols can also be applied in serum-form; bakuchiol, a naturally derived retinol is often more tolerable for dry skin.” Start with minimum concentrate retinol. You can start with &lt;u&gt;Tretin-A, 0.025%,&lt;/u&gt; which is easily available in your nearest drugstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serum Tip for dry skin:&lt;/strong&gt;
Invest in Hyaluronic Acid Serum as retinol is a drying ingredient that has plenty of benefits to your skin. Since you can’t avoid retinol, you have to have good hydrating serums with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;moisturizer&quot;&gt;Moisturizer:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a good moisturizer to hydrate the skin, regardless of the skin type. A good moisturizer for dry skin should have ceramides that do wonders for the skin. Something as gentle as the CeraVe moisturizer works best for the skin. &lt;u&gt;CeraVe, Cetaphil, lubriderm&lt;/u&gt; are few of the best dermatologists approved moisturizers for your dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moisturizer Tip for dry skin:&lt;/strong&gt;
Never buy products with parabens and denatured alcohol, ethyl alcohol, isopropyl alcohol, or benzyl alcohol. These are meant to penetrate your skin deeper but ultimately result in breakouts and drier skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eye-cream&quot;&gt;Eye Cream:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the under-eye area is more sensitive than others, it’s a lot drier, too. To protect the delicate area, be sure to use a rich eye cream every night before bed. If you’re using a good moisturizer and are short of budget, you may skip this step because eye creams are quite expensive.
&lt;u&gt;Himalaya Under Eye Cream&lt;/u&gt; however can fit right in your budget. However, &lt;u&gt;CeraVe's&lt;/u&gt; under eye cream can be your best pick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sunscreen&quot;&gt;Sunscreen:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what, do not skip this step in the AM. You have to wear your sunscreen no matter if you’re staying indoors or even wearing makeup. No matter the season, you need to keep your skin safe from the environment. Consider a serum-like formula that won’t give you a streaky white finish.
When buying one, always buy SPF 50++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Neutrogena's&lt;/u&gt; suncreen and &lt;u&gt;La Roche Posay's&lt;/u&gt; spf 50++ are the best pick sunscreen for dry skin. Also, &lt;u&gt;CeraVe&lt;/u&gt; can never be out of this list.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin Care Routine</category>
        
        <category>Oily Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser, Everything You Need to Know, Uses and Ingredients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the skincare community, there are many products that have been carrying a great reputation. Among them is a brand that has determined to help the community as they strive for the best formula, CeraVe. As a result, you have seen or heard how dermatologists recommend CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is great for those with normal to dry skin. Therefore, it is voted to be the best time and again.
CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser works to gently cleanse the skin. It helps restore its protective barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provides up to 24 hours of hydration. Most importantly, it is also great for a sensitive skin!
Seriously, so what else are we looking for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-should-you-opt-for-cerave-hydrating-facial-cleanser&quot;&gt;Why should you opt for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/cleansers/hydrating-facial-cleanser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;active-ingredients&quot;&gt;Active Ingredients:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser product label for key active ingredients are salicylic acid, hyaluronic acid and ceramides.
Other ingredients include oils that can help to moisturise skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hyaluronic-acid&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ingredient attracts hydration to the skin’s surface and helps the skin retain moisture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;ceramides-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ceramides: &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essential for healthy skin, ceramides help restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier. Well, way to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;free-of-fragrance&quot;&gt;Free of Fragrance:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dermatologists recommend using products without any added fragrance. Fragrances irritate already inflamed skin. No facial wash needs fragrance. Your skin is already suffering from irritation with acne and possible medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this product has botanical or plant-based fragrance. Non-comedogenic, non-irritating and fragrance-free. Certainly, one more reason to get that bottle of CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser right now! 
Formulated for Face:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser ingredient’s concentrations of the product are regulated differently for face and body.
They are different with higher concentrations of detergents in body products. As a result, may make them more damaging to sensitive facial skin.
So, never use the body products for your face!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use&quot;&gt;How To Use?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firstly, wet skin with lukewarm water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After that, massage cleanser into skin in a gentle, circular motion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, rinse and pat your face with a clean towel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally! You are good to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t you feel your face moisturised and plump already? To sum it up, you can always trust our recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cerave-hydrating-facial-cleanser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cerave-hydrating-facial-cleanser/</guid>
        
        <category>Face</category>
        
        <category>Cleanser</category>
        
        <category>CeraVe</category>
        
        <category>Dry Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
