<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sheeny Care</title>
    <description>Skin Care is made easy with Sheeny Care as we help you make skincare routines understand skincare products, talk about various skin care regimens, and give you insights on beauty products and services.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 23:01:19 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 23:01:19 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skincare Ingredients You Should Never Mix</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The skin is healthy, only if your skin barrier is strong. By using random products and mixing different skincare ingredients, you might disrupt the barrier of your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixing skincare ingredients could be tricky right, cause it may make or break your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are new to skincare and you feel like the do’s and dons of skincare ingredients are complex and confusing, don’t you worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read along to find out what skincare ingredients you shouldn’t combine at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-you-mix-with-retinol&quot;&gt;WHAT CAN YOU MIX WITH RETINOL?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/retinol-in-skin-care-uses-benefits/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;passionate about retinol&lt;/a&gt; since day one and if you think retinol exfoliates the skin, or if it is a pigment lighter, then you are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retinol aka vitamin A increases the skin cell turnover i.e. it replaces existing skin cells by creating new skin cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now think about the best time you can use it in your routine? It definitely suits best in your night skin care right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you may use it in the morning, but here’s the deal. Retinol will make your skin extremely sensitive to sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, it’s the most effective during the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-retinol-with-ahas-glycolic-mandelic-lactic-acid-and-bhas-salycilic-acid&quot;&gt;Can you mix RETINOL with AHA’s (Glycolic, Mandelic, Lactic acid) and BHA’s (Salycilic Acid)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what retinol does, the worst thing you could do with your skin is mixing retinol with AHAs and BHAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-salicylic-acid/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;reading a detail blog about AHA and BHA&lt;/a&gt;, you can have more clarity on the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing this mixture is gonna do is make your skin extremely dry, irritated and disrupt your skin barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it may cause excessive skin sensitivity, irritation, and redness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-retinol-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;Can you mix RETINOL with Vitamin C?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is also known as ascorbic acid. Ahem, yes an acid. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;benefits and uses of Vitamin C&lt;/a&gt; goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a simple example of why you should not mix retinol with vitamin c is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider mixing oil with water. You need to understand that vitamin C is water soluble and retinol is oil soluble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine mixing retinol and vitamin C and wishing it to be absorbed to create magic in the skin. Uh uh, does that even make sense to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the term has been simplified, you know the rules right? That you must not mix acids with retinol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-retinol-with-benzoyl-peroxide&quot;&gt;Can you mix RETINOL with Benzoyl Peroxide?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benzoyl peroxide is an antibiotic and skin peeling agent. Retinol and benzoyl peroxides work almost the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, instead of increasing the effectiveness, mixing retinol and benzoyl peroxide cancels each other out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it will make the skin extremely dry and irritated. You may also experience peeling, mild burning, stinging, scaling, swelling, and itching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a formulation of adapalene (a third-generation topical retinoid) and benzoyl peroxide called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1300826061/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1300826061&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=a0837ad6096abc90427c576d7b95a274&quot;&gt;Epiduo&lt;/a&gt;. This medicine is used to treat mild to moderate acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, unless you have a third degree acne vulgaris, please do not use Epiduo without a prescription from a dermatologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-you-mix-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;What can you mix with VITAMIN C?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this product has been a holy grail for most of us. To be honest, vitamin C broke me out so much and I do not use it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one rule you need to understand when using vitamin C is to not use any other ingredients in the same routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you heard me correct. Vitamin C improves the efficiency of sunscreen and protects the skin from the free radical damage. It serves no other purpose than this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it is an antioxidant, I find it useful only when using it in the morning specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-vitamin-c-with-ahas-and-bhas&quot;&gt;Can you mix VITAMIN C with AHA’s and BHA’s?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is paired best with sunscreen. It increases the effectiveness of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you pair vitamin C with AHA or BHA, the pH of the acid will be greater than the pH of your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this happens, I can guarantee redness, irritation, maybe a zit or two and a compromised skin barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you want that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-vitamin-c-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Can you mix VITAMIN C with NIACINAMIDE?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we try to simplify and understand each skincare ingredient, it’s often easier for us to determine what might work best for our skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide is a hyped ingredient&lt;/a&gt;. Like vitamin C, niacinamide is also an antioxidant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a simple formula of skincare, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One antioxidant cancels out the other antioxidant. One pigment lighter cancels out the other and so on and so forth.
And the answer to mixing niacinamide and vitamin C is NO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are skin care estheticians who would say yes, and would suggest that if your skin can handle it then go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our skin is not a science lab and we are not testing different products at the same time to see if our skin can handle it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-mix-with-aha--bha&quot;&gt;What can you mix with AHA &amp;amp; BHA?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it sounds all fancy but AHAs are (Glycolic, Lactic and Mandelic Acid) and BHA is just Salicylic acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AHA helps improve the skin texture by exfoliating the outer layer of the skin. BHA on the other hand penetrates deep and exfoliates the insides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to retinol, this ingredient also makes your skin sensitive to sunlight and you may want to avoid it during the day. Remeber to put a good sunscreen that protects your skin if you use AHA and BHA in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-aha-and-bha&quot;&gt;Can you mix AHA and BHA?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using both the acids together might sound exciting as a lot of work goes in the background however, it can result in dehydrated and irritated skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could also disrupt your skin barrier as this can lead to irritation and even eczema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I personally feel that in skin care, less is always more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two things you need to consider when using AHA and BHA is the purpose of using it and the concentration of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel that your skin is dull, and a physical exfoliator is too harsh for you then you can use AHA for replenishing your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to treat acne, you can use BHA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-mix-ahas-and-bhas-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Can you mix AHA’s and BHA’s WITH NIACINAMIDE?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acids have a low pH of 3-4, whereas niacinamide has a higher pH at around 5-7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you combine niacinamide with AHA’s and BHA’s, the pH of the niacinamide will increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that none of the product is going to penetrate inside the skin and do the actual work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If mixing different skincare ingredient would do too much for your skin, would you still use it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one mantra of mixing skincare ingredients is identifying what the ingredient is supposed to do. Next, you can identify, whether that ingredient targets your skin concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, if the answer is yes, then you can encorporate it in your skincare routine.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 21:38:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/mixing-skincare-ingredients/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mixing-skincare-ingredients/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Use Retinol and Vitamin C in Your Skincare Routine: The Right and Wrong Way to Apply Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/retinol-in-skin-care-uses-benefits/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;retinol&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;vitamin C&lt;/a&gt; products? If so, what were your initial thoughts on them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you just think they were great ingredients to have in everything and that you’re too old to care about their effects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a skincare enthusiast myself, I’ve been cleaning up my skincare ingredients for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to do so, then this article is for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll provide you with an unbiased look at what retinol and vitamin C can do for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a sample, please follow the guidelines below. Also, follow me to the end of the blog so you do not miss any important information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skincare-ingredients-that-dont-go-well-together.png&quot; alt=&quot;Skincare Ingredients You Should Never Mix&quot; title=&quot;Skincare Ingredients You Should Never Mix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard about all of these ingredients working on different areas of your skin but do not understand exactly what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is you can use these powerful ingredients, however, applying the products in the wrong way can be detrimental to your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right way to apply them can help your skin look younger, feel flattered, have less stress, and even help fight wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-you-apply-retinol-and-vitamin-c-at-the-same-time&quot;&gt;Can You Apply Retinol and Vitamin C at the Same Time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C and retinol (Vitamin A) are natural ingredients that help hydrate and strengthen your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you apply both of these products with care, they can work together to provide you with more lasting results (and less irritation) than either alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what you may experience if you unwisely use them for your skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;change-in-the-ph-level-of-your-face&quot;&gt;Change in the PH Level of Your Face:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When applying ingredients that are meant to be applied directly to the skin such as retinol or vitamin C, the pH of the skin is usually kept below 4.0 to increase their efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retinol:&lt;/b&gt; Retinol typically has a pH between 5.0 and 6.0, as research has shown that’s where it operates best. If you have dry, sensitive skin, you’re probably not going to want to raise its concentration too high.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vitamin C:&lt;/b&gt; The right pH level for vitamin C also means you need to be applying it at the right concentration level. Too much, and you risk irritation. L-Ascorbic Acid, the active form of vitamin C, needs to be at pH 3.5 or lower to effectively penetrate your skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get one thing straight: you can’t just apply these two products in the order I tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use them together, the pH gap between these two ingredients will lower each other’s effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oil-and-water-do-not-mix&quot;&gt;Oil and Water Do Not Mix:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used retinol and vitamin C on and off for just over a year now. My routine has slowly shifted from using them together to using them one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retinol:&lt;/b&gt; This one right here is oil soluble and only dissolves in oil.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vitamin C:&lt;/b&gt; This however is water-soluble and doesn’t dissolve otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also must give you a general idea to not mix these ingredients. If you do, they will just create a barrier in the skin but neither of the product will penetrate deep inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-apply-retinol-and-vitamin-c---the-best-ways&quot;&gt;How to Apply Retinol and Vitamin C - The Best Ways?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to use the retinol as a standalone product because I didn’t know if using a lower dosage would help or hurt anything, but as they say, “you can never have too many retinoids” (which I will admit makes me sound like a total skincare nut).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until I started researching more about using retinol and vitamin C together that I saw how beneficial this combination truly is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-vitamin-c-in-the-morning-retinol-at-night&quot;&gt;1. Vitamin C in the Morning, Retinol at Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retinol and vitamin C are both incredibly powerful tools in various skincare routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use vitamin C in the morning and retinol at night, you will avoid creating any new skin problems while potentially increasing the effectiveness of both retinol and vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-vitamin-c-and-retinol-on-alternate-nights&quot;&gt;2. Vitamin C and Retinol on Alternate Nights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know, retinol is a blockbuster ingredient found in high concentration in some products to use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has an incredibly wide range of potential benefits when it comes to skincare care, but most of us aren’t using it properly or at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But trust me when I say that giving your skin the lightning power of retinol and vitamin C on alternate nights is absolutely worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can be used on their own to give your skin the boost it needs especially when combined with a high-quality hyaluronic acid serum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-vitamin-c-and-retinol-at-night-30-minutes-apart&quot;&gt;3. Vitamin C and Retinol at Night, 30 Minutes Apart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use retinol and vitamin C effectively, you need to understand how they must be applied in a single skincare routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If applied incorrectly, these products will degrade your pH levels, which will make your skin look dry and flaky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you should first apply vitamin C, then wait half an hour before applying retinol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, your skin can return to a normal pH level in the waiting period, allowing each ingredient to work effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-vitamin-c-derivative-and-retinol-at-night&quot;&gt;4. Vitamin C Derivative and Retinol at Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, you might be aware that using retinol and vitamin C in your skincare routine is not without risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you still want to do so, and the half-hour window period still seems a long time, you can use derivatives of vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The derivatives of vitamin C tend to be more stable and less irritating and offer many of the same benefits (including protection from free radicals, brightening, and in some cases, even boosting collagen production).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-if-your-vitamin-c-treatment-is-anhydrous-water-free&quot;&gt;What if your vitamin C treatment is anhydrous (water-free)?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anhydrous solutions are water-free generally made up of oil. In that case, you can apply retinol first, let it absorb in the skin, and follow up with Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use them on alternate nights or different skincare routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-best-products-with-retinol&quot;&gt;The Best Products with Retinol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0779YGB2G/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0779YGB2G&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=3272b1c882846b1995c21478626e9911&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Retinol 1% in Squalane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KZSP4ZG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07KZSP4ZG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=17c0a129fb2420af37fa4ec34b5316fc&quot;&gt;Drunk Elephant A-Passioni Retinol Anti-Wrinkle Cream. Brightening, Restorative and Vegan Face Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07L1PHSY9/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07L1PHSY9&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=f6b758f2a2f99b43d6638ff76338481c&quot;&gt;Acne Treatment Differin Gel, Acne Spot Treatment for Face with Adapalene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00027DMI8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00027DMI8&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=41586a542cd2380e359f483bcf05ebd7&quot;&gt;RoC Retinol Correxion Deep Wrinkle Anti-Aging Retinol Night Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08147WH37/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B08147WH37&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=62cf8f00bd6efbc8fe0a779830350cde&quot;&gt;Olay Regenerist Retinol 24 Night Moisturizer Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-best-products-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;The Best Products with Vitamin C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000F6NX94/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000F6NX94&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=93e4584e17291e553db0ff85304ef0d2&quot;&gt;C E Ferulic Combination Antioxidant Treatment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B078KP3NSW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B078KP3NSW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=c800cb20c53896c073fb4f527d707497&quot;&gt;Clinique Fresh Pressed Daily Booster With Pure Vitamin C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07PNCCLD2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07PNCCLD2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=61b61d0472e05aa363adb2ba896f2bd1&quot;&gt;CeraVe Vitamin C Serum with Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0038COKQ2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0038COKQ2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=2d1cd4c41fce767f0edf3794877b0e15&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Redermic C Anti-Wrinkle Vitamin C Moisturizer with Pure Vitamin C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07GBNTPRY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07GBNTPRY&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=f67010cc577d56c7d290a52f6d844f73&quot;&gt;L’Oreal Paris Skincare Revitalift Derm Intensives 10% Pure Vitamin C Serum with Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, guys, thanks for sticking with me yet again. I will soon come up with other content as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no hidden costs involved and all opinions in this post are mine. I will also be making a certain amount of commission on the purchase of any of these items from the links as these are affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click on some of the links, I’ll assume you’re interested in the product as well as trust me in a certain level for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found something helpful. If you did, then I’ve accomplished my goal. Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, feel free to read on and help me out by following me on Pinterest: @sheenycare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/retinol-and-vitamin-c/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/retinol-and-vitamin-c/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Best Sunscreen for 2021 According to Dermatologists</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like your skin was on the worst side of the sun and it didn’t even matter what shirt you were wearing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve been told to wear light clothing and have suffered the burn, or maybe you just didn’t feel like spending money on a specific brand of sunscreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here’s my story: I knew summer was around the corner and I had to visit my dermatologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally made an appointment last Sunday. She then prescribed me one the best sunscreens for the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That made me think maybe sunscreen could probably be the solution to your messed-up life too and perhaps a liter or two of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list i’ve prepared is sunscreens that are suggested by my dermatologist. Let’s start with the basics and then we will get to the products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things people should understand is: &lt;b&gt;regardless of whether we need sunscreen.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun doesn’t disappear all of a sudden when it’s gloomy or cloudy. The sun is there and so are its powerful UV rays. Applying and reapplying sunscreen will prevent your skin from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Painful sunburns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skin cancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Premature signs of aging &amp;gt; dark spots and wrinkles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, &lt;b&gt;an SPF is indeed a Sun Protection Factor.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-choose-the-best-sunscreen-for-your-skin&quot;&gt;How to choose the best sunscreen for your skin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like the perfect sunscreen but there are categories however which make a specific sunscreen ideal for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Look for a broad-spectrum sunscreen:&lt;/b&gt; When buying a sunscreen, experts recommend an SPF 30 or higher. This ensures that the sunscreen you use will fight with the UVA and UVB’s. Also, when you’re doing an outdoor activity, you must choose an SPF of 50 and higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Find water-resistant sunscreens:&lt;/b&gt; It’s not about going for a swim, but water-resistant sunscreens will last long if you’re sweating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Choose cream-based sunscreen:&lt;/b&gt; There are many products available in the market. Today you can get sunscreens as a spray or stick or even like a loose powder. Despite the improvement in packaging, cream-based sunscreens are easy to use, they can be applied evenly and absorb better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-top-10-sunscreens-of-2021&quot;&gt;The Top 10 Sunscreens of 2021:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s get straight to the point. I have done my part and found the best 10 sunscreens of 2021, all recommended by board-specified dermatologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-eltamd-uv-clear-facial-sunscreen-spf-46--sunscreen-for-sensitive-or-acne-prone-skin&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002MSN3QQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002MSN3QQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=1e526858acebb8dcbe41505d70583d98&quot;&gt;EltaMD UV Clear Facial Sunscreen SPF 46 | Sunscreen for Sensitive or Acne-Prone Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was first taught about sunscreen by my mom, she gave me the Elta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, who was a complete beginner, used it and honestly liked it very much. When I further dug into the product, it was oil-Free and had mineral-based zinc oxide formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom knew about this sunscreen from her derm. This sunscreen specifically calms and protects sensitive skin types prone to acne, rosacea, and discoloration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen lotion is non-greasy, fragrance-free, oil-free, paraben-free, sensitivity-free, and noncomedogenic. It is available in tinted and untinted formulas for everyday UVA and UVB sun protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/elta-md-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;EltaMD UV Clear Facial Sunscreen SPF 46&quot; title=&quot;EltaMD UV Clear Facial Sunscreen SPF 46&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-neutrogena-ultra-sheer-dry-touch-sunscreen-spf-100--sunscreen-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002JAYMEE/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002JAYMEE&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=944e3c00d261da48cdbd7cffb407678e&quot;&gt;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen SPF 100+ | Sunscreen for Oily Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen is always on my shelf, like always. Part of the reason I always have it is that it comes in my budget and works the same as the expensive ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it is easily available, I must say. This product claims to defend against the signs of sun and decrease the risk of skin cancer caused by the sun when used as directed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about this product is that it has a non-greasy matte finish and is a non-comedogenic, paraben-free sunscreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen is also available in both spray and stick form and can be used at the pool or in the ocean for up to 80 minutes of water resistance (linked below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07CYTB3KJ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07CYTB3KJ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=41c8f68c0e9a9c763c61f63c1c4d2cff&quot;&gt;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Spf100 +Body Mist Full Reach Spray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00HNSSV3U/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00HNSSV3U&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=ce3ad5d6044c64554db67b411eb02974&quot;&gt;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Non-Greasy Sunscreen Stick  SPF 70 UVA/UVB Sunscreen Stick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/neutrogena-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen SPF 100+&quot; title=&quot;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen SPF 100+&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-banana-boat-ultra-sport-reef-friendly-spf-50--sunscreen-for-all-skin-types&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004CDV7EY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004CDV7EY&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=eb2cd35833834ab11e06517c39fcab6b&quot;&gt;Banana Boat Ultra Sport Reef Friendly SPF 50 | Sunscreen for All Skin Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember using banana boat sunscreen as a child when going to swim. I would put tons and tons of it, layer it all over my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my research, I found that this is still one of the most trusted brands, and people have been going back to this product. Even my brother who rarely puts moisturizer makes sure to use this when going to swim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen is clinically proven to provide UVA/UVB protection. It actually absorbs pretty quickly and won’t weigh you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is designed for active and outdoor use so has a high-performance rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most of us use it before swimming, sweat and water are of no concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banana Boat stays on in the sun, pool water, ocean water, wind, sweat, sand, and extreme heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/banana-boat-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Banana Boat Ultra Sport Reef Friendly Sunscreen&quot; title=&quot;Banana Boat Ultra Sport Reef Friendly Sunscreen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-australian-gold-botanical-sunscreen-spf-50--sunscreen-for-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01M8G39OW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01M8G39OW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=81b585320239dd10be3060f9034ae3ce&quot;&gt;Australian Gold Botanical Sunscreen SPF 50 | Sunscreen for Sensitive Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a blogger, I tend to be super honest with you, and honestly guys this product right here is so hard to find where I live and I must say the hype is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a non-chemical 100% mineral sunscreen. It contains Titanium Dioxide and Zinc Oxide which help provide a non-chemical sun protection option, with a powder-like matte finish that’s never greasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is made up of antioxidants from native Australian botanicals like Kakadu Plum, Eucalyptus, and Red Algae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australian gold perfectly protects your skin from both UVA and UVB rays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This non-chemical sunscreen lotion delivers a refreshingly luxurious, powdery-clean feel, while the subtle tint seamlessly blends into any skin tone yet washes away with water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is specifically formulated for sensitive skin and gentle to all other skin types as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/australian-gold-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Australian Gold Botanical Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; title=&quot;Australian Gold Botanical Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-blue-lizard-sunscreen-spf-30--sunscreen-for-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01MPZVN0U/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01MPZVN0U&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=904f624809097f1bcc74fb4d256b49cf&quot;&gt;Blue Lizard Sunscreen SPF 30+ | Sunscreen for Sensitive Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the few sunscreen brands that claim to protect the coral reefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen contains no Oxybenzone or Octinoxate harmful for the corals. This is a mineral sunscreen and reflects the harmful UV rays before entering the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SPF 30+ formula starts with Zinc Oxide to provide true broad-spectrum protection from 97% of the sun’s burning rays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is specifically formulated for sensitivity and contains no skin-irritating chemical sunscreen ingredients, no parabens, and no fragrances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provides head-to-toe sun protection and up to 40 minutes of water resistance, so you stay protected longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blue-lizard-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Lizard Sunscreen SPF 30+ &quot; title=&quot;Blue Lizard Sunscreen SPF 30+ &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-sun-bum-mineral-spf-50-sunscreen--sunscreen-for-all-skin-types&quot;&gt;6. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0721M83FL/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0721M83FL&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=1063fe23c57de2df42202f1f95ff5dea&quot;&gt;Sun Bum Mineral SPF 50 Sunscreen | Sunscreen for All Skin Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mineral-based sunscreen is a stick sunscreen so you can easily roll on the stick to your face, or where ever you wish to apply it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formula sticks on top of your face and since it is a mineral sunscreen, reflects the harmful UV rays before entering your body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formula is lightweight and silky, and this product is sure to leave your skin feeling clean, natural, and protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen enriched with Zinc Oxide and is hypoallergenic. It is specifically formulated for people who live on the beach and need products that work on the most intense days in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sun Bum sunscreen is also reef-friendly, free of oxybenzone and octinoxate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sun-bum-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sun Bum Mineral SPF 50 Sunscreen &quot; title=&quot;Sun Bum Mineral SPF 50 Sunscreen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-supergoop-glowscreen-spf-40--sunscreen-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;7. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B088ZRZ668/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B088ZRZ668&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=81e07e26f4f8e2f9b044c20eebb9c0e9&quot;&gt;Supergoop! Glowscreen SPF 40++ | Sunscreen for Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if sunscreen could double as a pump? What if you could benefit from broad-spectrum sun protection with SPF 40?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what Supergoop! Glowscreen sun protection system is all about. It contains ultra-violet rays (UVA) that penetrate deep into the skin for detoxification and antioxidant protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus its UVA protection is twice as powerful as any UVA protection found in competitor brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supergoop! Glowscreen SPF 40++ is, quite simply, the best sunscreen I’ve used. With hyaluronic acid, vitamin B5 &amp;amp; niacinamide, this face sunscreen leaves skin naturally supple and dewy from the inside out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun can penetrate deeply into your skin without likely causing acne and the best thing about this sunscreen is that it stays put—for the majority of the day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It prevents me from sweating while still allowing enough heat to escape for my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/supergoop-glowscreen-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Supergoop! Glowscreen SPF 40++&quot; title=&quot;Supergoop! Glowscreen SPF 40++&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-cerave-100-mineral-sunscreen-spf-50--sunscreen-for-sensitive-skin-&quot;&gt;8. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KLY4RYG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07KLY4RYG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=1e764a980cef1ad18858e21517eeee20&quot;&gt;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50 | Sunscreen for Sensitive Skin &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of CeraVe? If you haven’t, CeraVe is a “plug &amp;amp; play” skincare brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe’s 100% mineral-based sunscreen is the best all-rounder for anyone looking to protect their skin from the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other sunscreens, Cerave’s sunscreen contains no oxybenzone (retinol), which blocks the UVB rays but may cause either dark spots or oily skin on people with dark skin or those with acne resistant skins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whether you’re after a lighter, more tan-colored look or a more permanent change, Cerave’s sun protectant is worth taking a look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe’ highly ergonomic SPF 50 has been formulated with three ceramides to lock in moisture, ensuring you get all-day protection without fading or dryness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cerave-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; title=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-la-roche-posay-tinted-mineral-spf-50--sunscreen-for-all-skin-types-&quot;&gt;9. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007U54P36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B007U54P36&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=70f4500ed82ba5d3f8d394ac2c7d3da6&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Tinted Mineral SPF 50 | Sunscreen for All Skin Types &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La Roche-Posay Anthelios Tinted Mineral Ultra-Light Fluid Broad Spectrum SPF 50 gives even skin tones and a soft, fresh appearance whilst providing the vital protection of pure mineral sunscreens with SPF 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lightweight fluid combines mineral filters to deliver broad-spectrum UVA/UVB protection and antioxidants to protect from free radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light formula absorbs quickly to ensure a non-greasy finish and is comfortable to wear all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tinted SPF 50 formula eliminates the need for foundation or additional makeup, reducing the need for regular touch-ups throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/la-roche-posay-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;La Roche-Posay Tinted Mineral SPF 50&quot; title=&quot;La Roche-Posay Tinted Mineral SPF 50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-aveeno-daily-sunscreen-spf-70--sunscreen-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;10. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07J5NRJBB/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07J5NRJBB&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=f692ec5fba45958378a96f490f4dd198&quot;&gt;Aveeno Daily Sunscreen SPF 70 | Sunscreen for Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aveeno Protect + Hydrate Moisturizing Daily Sunscreen Lotion is a fast-absorbing, water-resistant lotion that’s ideal for everyday use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With broad-spectrum SPF 70 sunscreen to help protect skin from the sun’s harmful rays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This nourishing facial sunscreen is also enriched with antioxidant oat and hydrating skin conditioners to leave it feeling soft and healthier than before you went in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is perfectly suitable for use on the face and body, it provides UVA and UVB sun protection to help prevent sunburns and signs of premature skin aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s lightweight formula is fast-absorbing, oil-free and non-comedogenic, so it won’t clog pores, and is sweat-resistant and water-resistant for up to 80 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SPF 70 oil-free sunscreen lotion is recommended by the Skin Cancer Foundation as an effective broad spectrum sunscreen Apply sunscreen lotion prior to sun exposure to protect skin during outdoor activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aveeno-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Aveeno Daily Sunscreen SPF 70&quot; title=&quot;Aveeno Daily Sunscreen SPF 70&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, guys, thanks for sticking with me yet again. I will soon come up with other content as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no hidden costs involved and all opinions in this post are mine. I will also be making a certain amount of comission on the purchase of any of these items from the links as these are affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click on some of the links, I’ll assume you’re interested in the product as well as trust me in a certain level for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found something helpful. If you did, then i’ve accomplished my goal. Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/best-sunscreen-2021/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/best-sunscreen-2021/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 10 Best Ceramide Moisturizers to Buy in 2021 for Your Skin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently getting so many questions from my fellow followers and friends about ceramide, products with ceramide, and some famous ceramide capsules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt as if ceramide suddenly was a very big deal. Yes, I mean it is, but still, since everyone was asking about it, I thought of doing a proper blog about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, here’s a blog that I’ve already written about ceramide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Everything you need to know about Ceramides is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I’ll still give a heads up on the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ceramide is like blood, or organs we already have in our body. Except it is a form of liquid present in our skin. It’s as natural as hairs on our skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, with ceramide the skin is able to maintain moisture preventing any kind of dryness, itching, or irritation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might as well think that “Oh! is it just for dry skin?”, and my answer is NO. Why would anything be only made for dry skin, when it is natural and found in every skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you can increase the amount of ceramide in your body by eating good foods high in ceramides such as Soybeans, dairy, eggs, sweet potatoes, wheat germ, corn, and brown rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s get straight to the topic. Here are the list if the best skin barrier repair products packed with ceramide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-10-products-with-ceramide&quot;&gt;Top 10 Products With Ceramide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-la-roche-posay-toleriane-double-repair-face-moisturizer--all-skin-types&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01N9SPQHQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01N9SPQHQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=ebf741de1029b82bd55ca5f1e70c547e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer | All skin types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This moisturizer is the best. I’ve said so many times and I say it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This special formula works for all skin types. It is an oil-free face moisturizer that helps hydrate and restores healthy-looking skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is formulated with a high concentration of prebiotic thermal water, Ceramide-3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;Niacinamide&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; Glycerin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product is suitable for your gentle face and hands. And the best part is they have tested it on sensitive skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/laroche-posay-toleraine-moisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;La Roche-Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer&quot; title=&quot;La Roche-Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2--cerave-moisturizing-cream--dry-skin&quot;&gt;2. 	&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00TTD9BRC/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00TTD9BRC&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=f171b585ab8f2ff10404ddd4f10869bd&quot;&gt;CeraVe Moisturizing Cream | Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, CeraVe has been the talk of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially, its CeraVe Moisturizing Cream has a unique formula that provides 24-hour hydration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It helps restore the protective skin barrier with three essential ceramides (1,3,6-II). The formula also contains hyaluronic acid to help retain the skin’s natural moisture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a non-comedogenic, fragrance-free, gentle, non-irritating, and paraben-free formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Moisturizing Cream has a rich, velvety texture that is non-greasy. It is absorbed real quickly, leaving the skin smooth and hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is not greasy guys, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cerave-moisturizer-cream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CeraVe Moisturizing Cream&quot; title=&quot;CeraVe Moisturizing Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3--beautystat-universal-pro-bio-moisture-boost-cream--sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;3. 	&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0862CZCK3/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0862CZCK3&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=5cffc2d4ce8d78d67327931702108fe4&quot;&gt;BeautyStat Universal Pro-Bio Moisture Boost Cream | Sensitive Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This moisturizer is the perfect example of a perfect day and night cream. Well that’s what the product redeems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An all-in-one day cream, night cream, and wrinkle cream. It is 24 hours of quenching and age-fighting formula that locks in the moisture all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wrinkle cream’s job is to lock in moisture using Hyaluronic Acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, this product protects the very health of your face using Ganoderma, an ancient ferment derived from a rare mushroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover it has Bifida Extract, a beneficial probiotic, that when combined helps heal, detoxify, soothe and fight environmental pollution that can cause aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/beautystat-cosmetic-moisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;BeautyStat Universal Pro-Bio Moisture Boost Cream&quot; title=&quot;BeautyStat Universal Pro-Bio Moisture Boost Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-cerave-eczema-relief-creamy-body-oil--eczema&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08PCV4QNH/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B08PCV4QNH&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=dba3d13a1bd72e1362d53d02881cd287&quot;&gt;Cerave Eczema Relief Creamy Body Oil | Eczema&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product contains Colloidal Oatmeal to help relieve symptoms of eczema, such as dry, itchy, scaly patches of skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also contains Safflower Oil that helps to moisturize skin, while hyaluronic acid helps to hydrate skin and retain natural moisture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Eczema Relief Creamy Oil has a rich, occlusive texture that feels like a combination of a moisturizing cream and a body oil all in one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is absorbed real quickly, leaving the skin smooth and hydrated. In other words, it doesn’t make your skin greasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the main part here is that it contains three essential ceramides (1, 3, 6-II) to help restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cerave-eczema-cream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cerave Eczema Relief Creamy Body Oil&quot; title=&quot;Cerave Eczema Relief Creamy Body Oil&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-paulas-choice-clear-oil-free-moisturizer--acne-prone-skin&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07HZWXGJ7/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07HZWXGJ7&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=3037cb10b190e48c3da4c2183b3efce3&quot;&gt;Paula’s Choice CLEAR Oil-Free Moisturizer | Acne-Prone Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dear people with acne, here’s a weightless moisturizer for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This moisturizer delivers moisture and hydration without adding oil or shine or any type of greasing in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is infused with moisture barrier-repairing ceramides, pore-minimizing niacinamide, and antioxidant-rich blueberry &amp;amp; pumpkin extracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This face moisturizer hydrates dry, flaky patches while visibly reducing redness - all without clogging pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it is the ultimate non-greasy moisturizer for both daytime and nighttime use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/paulas-choice-oil-free-moisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Paula&apos;s Choice CLEAR Oil-Free Moisturizer&quot; title=&quot;Paula&apos;s Choice CLEAR Oil-Free Moisturizer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-mario-badescu-aha--ceramide-moisturizer--dull-skin&quot;&gt;6. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001HLA6YG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001HLA6YG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=281623e30873d6941ed42ea9e0c841d1&quot;&gt;Mario Badescu A.H.A. &amp;amp; Ceramide Moisturizer | Dull Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product is super gentle even after containing alpha hydroxy acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is formulated with lemon extract and soothing aloe vera gel. It is non-greasy, absorbent and very lightweight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this moisturizer is to revive and rejuvenate dull and congested skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mario-badescu-moisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Mario Badescu A.H.A. and Ceramide Moisturizer&quot; title=&quot;Mario Badescu A.H.A. and Ceramide Moisturizer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-elizabeth-arden-retinol-ceramide-capsules--aging-skin&quot;&gt;7. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07FCS2HHB/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07FCS2HHB&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=8adc418f7a2c85a2d11c4ce279e71926&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Arden Retinol Ceramide Capsules | Aging Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are my luxurious people tired of this product being out of stock time and again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time you find it, bring it home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This luxurious, lightweight, semi-translucent serum combines two of the biggest names in skincare in one, easy-to-use capsule: Retinol, the clinically proven wrinkle-smoother, and moisture-boosting ceramides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sealed for freshness and potency, this formula provides visible results while helping to protect against the dryness and irritation often associated with retinol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never sticky or tacky, this serum absorbs quickly and completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/elizabeth-arden-capsule.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Elizabeth Arden Retinol Ceramide Capsules&quot; title=&quot;Elizabeth Arden Retinol Ceramide Capsules&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-ceramedx---ultra-moisturizing-natural-ceramide-cream--sensitive-skin-&quot;&gt;8. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07BZCDQCD/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07BZCDQCD&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=2fa0294b34891dfe1eea23f437fed893&quot;&gt;CERAMEDX - Ultra Moisturizing Natural Ceramide Cream | Sensitive Skin &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product is a natural ceramide therapy for dry and sensitive skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is fragrance-free and moisturizes intensive dry skin. The product relieves, soothes and protects sensitive skin, and severely dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it is formulated with hyaluronic acid and shea butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the Exclusive Riceramide-3 Complex absorbs into the skin to nourish, hydrate and replenish the skin’s natural moisture barrier and support skin renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the ceramides, moisturizers and active ingredients in this product is plant-based and not chemically or synthetically derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ceramedx-moisturizer-cream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CERAMEDX - Ultra Moisturizing Natural Ceramide Cream&quot; title=&quot;CERAMEDX - Ultra Moisturizing Natural Ceramide Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-drjart--ceramidin-liquid--dry-skin&quot;&gt;9. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B012YKNY9C/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B012YKNY9C&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=080df40e4df6d8b293ed6d0800b0dac7&quot;&gt;Dr.jart + Ceramidin Liquid | Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you want your toner to moisturize your skin? Well if you want, leave it to Dr. Jart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well not literally find Dr. Jart but instead gift yourslef this lightweight, fast-absorbing fluid that balances skin and leaves your complexion feeling supple and hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, go get this product and see how it works wonder for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dr-jart-ceramidin-liquid.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Dr.jart + Ceramidin Liquid&quot; title=&quot;Dr.jart + Ceramidin Liquid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-first-aid-beauty-ultra-repair-cream-intense-hydration-moisturizer--sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;10. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0065I0UMO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0065I0UMO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=77c1e1d50a0b3c24ee3cd0c66c44b025&quot;&gt;First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream Intense Hydration Moisturizer | Sensitive Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This award winning First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream works wonders in winter and beats winter dryness in a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is infused with soothing colloidal oatmeal, shea butter, and ceramide 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the hydration wonder leaves even the most dry, flakey skin feeling smooth and hydrated. And the good news is, it is safe for sensitive skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it also concerns Eczema, Dryness, Fine Lines, Wrinkles, and Redness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/first-aid-beauty-cream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream&quot; title=&quot;First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, guys, thanks for sticking with me yet again. I will soon come up with other contents as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the links in this post are affiliate links and I might get a certain amount of commission on any purchase through the link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope you like what you read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/best-ceramide-skin-care-products/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/best-ceramide-skin-care-products/</guid>
        
        <category>Moisturizer</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Different Types Of Acne And How To Cure Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi people, I’m back again and today we will be talking about the different types of acne and how to treat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am super nervous while I’m writing this because I intend to be the Wikipedia of acne today. Apparently, I never have had problems with or by acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, from someone who really doesn’t care about acne to you who is down here because acne has taken over your life, I will help you identify the different types of acne and give insights on how to treat them with some pictures that helps you indentify if you have any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, before digging right down the topic, I’d like to ask you something: do you understand what are the different types of acne and what type of acne do you have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, I’d like to start this post with the smallest of details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-acne&quot;&gt;What is acne?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Acne is a skin condition that occurs when your hair follicles become plugged with oil and dead skin cells. Clogged pores cause acne as well. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acne can be simplified into simpler terms: blemishes, bumps, pimples, breakouts, and many more. The most general name to describe all kinds of acne is “breakout”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acne usually appears on the face, forehead, chest, upper back, and shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either you are a teenager who got their first acne or an adult who is fed up with acne, you need to brace yourself because the game of acne is pretty dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the acne you know is only the “pimple” acne but apparently, acne doesn’t like to be of only one form. If you’re interested to know about the different types of acne then let’s head further together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-main-causes-of-acne&quot;&gt;What are the main causes of acne?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the pores in our skin don’t let go of oil and dirt, it helps create acne. The other attributes that may cause acne are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;excess production of oil (sebum)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bacteria&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hormones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dead skin cells and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ingrown hairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-different-types-of-acne&quot;&gt;What are the different types of acne?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acne has many forms, many types and all the credit goes to clogged pores. The different types of acne are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Inflammatory Acne &lt;/b&gt; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Non-Inflammatory Acne &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first ever acne was right before I got my first period. And ever since that I almost am concerned about hormonal acne and nothing else. So you know now that acne is usually associated with hormonal fluctuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, you too must have had your first acne during your teenage years. The easiest method to treat acne by far is by identifying which type of acne you’re experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It is possible to have multiples types of acne at once i.e you can experience both inflammatory and non-inflammatory acne at once.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subtypes of acne are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blackheads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whiteheads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;papules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pustules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nodules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cysts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the most common signs and symptoms of acne. You may have an ignorable to severe condition of any of the different types of acne mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, before it is too late, you must identify what kind of acne you have and if you need help from a dermatologist or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-know-what-type-of-acne-do-i-have&quot;&gt;How do I know what type of acne do I have?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to identify whether you have a blackhead, pustule, or something else for yourself. In some cases, people are mistaken for several other issues that appear like acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Acne can form several types of skin blemish, each with a distinct appearance and symptoms.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s find out what different types of acne blemishes looks like and treat them. If you’re super concerned about your acne then I do recommend a visit to dermatologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;non-inflammatory-acne&quot;&gt;Non-Inflammatory Acne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I was super amazed when I found out that even blackheads or whiteheads are acne. Well, this definitely meant that my face was full of mild acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all my acne is non-inflammatory. In simpler terms, not all acne looks like huge bumps like speed breakers on the road. Well, all my pores are clogged and if I happen to pinch anywhere, small white dots pop out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clogged pores cause acne. The types of acne that you may experience under non-inflammatory ones are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Whiteheads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blackheads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key ingredient that is used to treat non-inflammatory acne is Salicylic Acid. Salicylic acid helps deep cleanse the pores by exfoliating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check Out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-salicylic-acid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What salicylic acid is and why you must have it for treating acne.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blackheads-open-comedones&quot;&gt;Blackheads (open comedones)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackheads are the result of a combination of dead skin cells and excess sebum production. Well, to identify if you have blackheads or not, refer to the following picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the top of the pore stays open whereas the rest of the pore is clogged. Hence, you see a black dot on the surface of your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blackheads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whiteheads-closed-comedones&quot;&gt;Whiteheads (closed comedones)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other type of non-inflammatory acne is whiteheads. This type of acne is medically known as closed-comedones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whitehead is a type of acne that forms when dead skin cells, oil, and bacteria become trapped within one of your pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are small, whitish, or flesh-colored spots or bumps. The entire pore is clogged (closed) starting from the head of the pore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither blackhead nor whitehead pimple can be removed or fixed by squeezing them. Therefore it is important you realize that picking them up will only lead to scarring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/whiteheads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-treat-blackheads-and-whiteheads&quot;&gt;How to treat blackheads and whiteheads?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to treat different types of acne. Often, active ingredients are used to treat non-inflammatory acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moisturizers, gels, toners, and creams with a mix of active ingredients are the different types of acne medication that can treat non-inflammatory acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few over-the-counter(OTC) whitehead and blackhead treatments that include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sulfur (may take up to 3 months before you begin to see results)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salicylic acid (takes 2-12 weeks to treat acne)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;benzoyl peroxide (starts from 4 weeks of application and takes up to 2-4 months for the treatment to have a full effect)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;resorcinol (available only with your doctors prescription)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, when choosing one of these OTC to treat whiteheads and blackheads to stop such pimples coming on the face, you need to understand that these treatments require patience and consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;inflammatory-acne&quot;&gt;Inflammatory acne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kinds of pimples that are red and swollen are called inflammatory acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember when I said all I cared about is my hormonal acne because yes, they get super big, red, is painful when touched, and also leava a slight mark of its visit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, sebum and dead skin cells contribute to inflammatory acne. In addition, bacteria also plays a vital role in clogging the pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sole reason why your pimple may hurt is that these stupid bacterias cause an infection deep beneath your skin’s surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, inflammatory acne blemishes includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;papules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pustules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nodules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cysts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;minor-to-mild-acne&quot;&gt;Minor to Mild Acne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;papules&quot;&gt;Papules&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papules are comedones that become inflamed and form small red bumps on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They occur when the walls surrounding your pores break down from severe inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike whiteheads, papules have no visible center. Unlike blackheads, the pores of a papule do not appear to be widened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papules develop when whiteheads or blackheads cause so much irritation that they damage some of the surrounding skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the damage leads to inflammation and the skin around these pores is usually pink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/papules.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pustules&quot;&gt;Pustules&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pustules are larger, tender bumps with a defined circular center. The center is filled with whitish or yellowish pus, and the bump has a pink or red base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immune cells and bacterial cells collect to form this pus. They resemble whiteheads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, pustules can also form when the walls around your pores break down. They typically look like much larger and more inflamed whiteheads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pustules.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-treat-pustules-and-papules&quot;&gt;How to treat pustules and papules?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor to mild papules and pustules can be treated with several home remedies as well as over the counter medicines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other workds, you have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wash the affected area twice a day using cool water and clean hands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you may also apply gentle facecloth twice a day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;apply a warm compress to the affected area for 10-15 minutes to allow the trapped debris to rise to the surface.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use products with benzoyl peroxide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use products with salicylic acid to remove dead skin cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nodules&quot;&gt;Nodules&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nodules are large, inflamed bumps that feel firm to the touch. They develop deep within the skin and are often painful. Nodules should be treated by a dermatologist since they can scar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over-the-counter treatments may not be powerful enough to clear them up, but prescription drugs can be effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sooner you start treatment, the fewer permanent scars you’ll have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nodule.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cysts&quot;&gt;Cysts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cysts are very large, soft, painful, red or white lumps situated deep in the skin. They are filled with pus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who develop nodules and cysts are usually considered to have a more severe form of acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like nodules, cysts can be painful and should be treated by a dermatologist since they also can scar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyst.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Different types of acne with pictures&quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Acne with Pictures&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-treat-nodules-and-cysts&quot;&gt;How to treat nodules and cysts?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderate to severe nodules and cysts cannot be treated at home and these require care from a doctor or dermatologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In adition, doctors may use many products and procedures to treat nodules and cysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;oral contraceptives for hormonal-related acne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;systematic retinoids, such as isotretinoin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;antibiotics, such as tetracycline, doxycycline, and amoxicillin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;topical corticosteroids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;steroid injections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chemical peels that are available in pharmacies or online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;photodynamic therapy to combat bacteria&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drainage and extraction to remove large cysts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;home-remedies-to-treat-different-types-of-acne&quot;&gt;Home remedies to treat different types of acne.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several home remedies and lifestyle changes that may help treat or reduce acne to some extend. A few of the remedies that you may try are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;washing the face with lukewarm water twice a day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bathing every 2 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eating a healthy and balanced diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;staying hydrated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;limiting exposure to the sun and wearing sunscreen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reducing stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/different-types-of-acne-how-to-cure-them/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/different-types-of-acne-how-to-cure-them/</guid>
        
        <category>Acne Types</category>
        
        <category>Acne Treatment</category>
        
        
        <category>Acne</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Affordable Skin Care Products For Dry Skin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello readers, today I am writing on dry skin yet again and if you have one, I can completely understand you. I too have dry skin, well yes, severely dry. I have been struggling with this condition for way too long. Like everyone else, I too google how to get rid of dry skin the winter or about the best skincare for dry skin and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then you must be saying, “Oh, what is she even talking about, she is a skincare blogger, she must have great skin!”. I’m afraid I don’t because my skin sucks as well. As a skincare blogger, I care for my skin but in reality, my skin is as messed up as everyone else’s. Well, my condition is genetic and nothing actually works for me other than constant care and effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skin is dry&lt;/a&gt; or if you wish to find it out, then you have landed in the right place. You can also read about building the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-dry-skin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;best skin care routine&lt;/a&gt; for dry skin and enhance your knowledge on this scope. Now let’s get on with products that generally work for dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-skincare-products-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Best skincare products for dry skin.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-cetaphil-gentle-skin-cleanser-1155&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07GC74LL5/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=39cb6a2561603724e63ea0bf03976d5b&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07GC74LL5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Gentle Skin Cleanser ($11.55)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cetaphil gentle skin cleanser can be used daily to gently clean, hydrate, and soothe dry, sensitive skin. I have been using it ever since I came to know about it. This gentle face wash is suitable for all skin types but it is ideal for dry, sensitive skin. The formula is pH balanced, fragrance-free, and hypoallergic. The one thing that made love this product was the fact that it is gentle enough to use with or without water. It is a product recommended by dermatologist and even I recommend you to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cetaphil-gentle-skin-cleanser.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cetaphil Gentle Skin Cleanser&quot; title=&quot;Cetaphil Gentle Skin Cleanser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-cerave-hydrating-facial-cleanser-1464&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MSSDEPK/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=4cba6458ea95de36dab25f8fe88aac73&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01MSSDEPK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe Hydrating Facial Cleanser ($14.64)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember when Cerave was super hyped? Like everyone was talking about it. Every dermatologist on Instagram and TikTok was going crazy about it, skincare estheticians couldn’t stop recommending it? That is when I decided to buy one no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gentle cleansing lotion contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hyaluronic acid&lt;/a&gt;, essential &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-ceramide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ceramides&lt;/a&gt;, and glycerin to help hydrate skin without stripping out the moisture. It helps in removing makeup, dirt, and excess oil. It also provides 24-hour hydration and leaves a moisturized, non-greasy feel as it has lotion-like consistency which makes the skin feel smooth as it cleanses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cerave-hydrating-cleansers.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cerave Hydrating Facial Cleanser&quot; title=&quot;Cerave Hydrating Facial Cleanser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-banila-clean-it-zero-1754&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07BSV1T35/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=ba53b295b793f08672bb8aa804fef511&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07BSV1T35&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Banila Clean It Zero ($17.54)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil cleansers is a good alternative to micellar water. This double cleansing technique is the best thing I have learned ever since I indulged myself in skincare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally love using oil in my skincare routine and this oil cleanser dissolves any product we use on our face, resulting in a clear skin after washing off. Furthermore, Banila’s clean it zero is my favorite. Its main ingredients are emulsifying alcohol and palm oil, and it doesn’t leave residue on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is not actually fragrance free and if you’re sensitive to fragrances, handle this product with care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/banilacleanitzero.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Banila Clean It Zero&quot; title=&quot;Banila Clean It Zero&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-instanatural-vitamin-c-serum-1675&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IDWP4IA/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=11431687f883e563a60b468eaa82e757&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IDWP4IA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum ($16.75)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have said this so many times, and I will repeat it, that I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt;  in my Vitamin C. In fact both of this ingredient are a must in anyone’s skincare routine well when you get them both together you should click the buy now button. This was the first and special ingredient I added to my skincare routine after I turned 18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/instanaturalvitc.webp&quot; alt=&quot;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum &quot; title=&quot;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-cetaphil-moisturizing-cream-1288&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B086LJQNB2/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=c7051c06b2db4419f8f089153a27f3f1&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B086LJQNB2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Moisturizing Cream ($12.88)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been complementing cetaphil everywhere and that’s because I have been using their range since a very long time. One of the reasons why I am still using it is because their products are effective yet non-irritating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cetaphil moisturizing cream provides immediate and lasting 24-hour relief from dry to very dry skin. It completely restores the skin barrier in a week and binds water to the skin. Therefore, it prevents moisture loss in the skin to hydrate and protect skin from dryness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cetaphil-moisturizing-cream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cetaphil Moisturizing Cream&quot; title=&quot;Cetaphil Moisturizing Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-cerave-daily-moisturizing-lotion-for-dry-skin-1778&quot;&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RK4HST7/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=e409f50f737201d80c4cf1320bea514e&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07RK4HST7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe Daily Moisturizing Lotion for Dry Skin ($17.78)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerave and fine wine are the same. The more the merrier. Fine wine also have some excellent properties and can contribute to healthy skin but Cerave indeed is one of a kind. It has a smooth, light-weight texture which is quickly absorbed by our skin. It even contains Hyaluronic Acid to help retain natural moisture and ceramides to help restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cerave-moisturizing-lotion.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cerave Moisturizing Lotion&quot; title=&quot;Cerave Moisturizing Lotion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-la-roche-posay-toleriane-ultra-cream-1499&quot;&gt;7. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01N9SPQHQ/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=5191eb7e2676d7ad7d56198e652ce591&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01N9SPQHQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream ($14.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first tried this moisturizer when I once in a while have an urge to try products that I have never used before. My friend from Australia sent me a package of La Roche Posay and well I have turned to absolutely love it. I even recommend this to people with oily skin because the formulation is too good be true for all skin types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This face moisturizer provides up to 48-hour hydration and helps restore skin’s barrier. It is also non comodogenic i.e it won’t clog pores. It is formulated with a high concentration of Prebiotic Thermal Water, Ceramide-3, Niacinamide &amp;amp; Glycerin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/larocheposaymoisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream&quot; title=&quot;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-the-ordinary-hyaluronic-acid-1200&quot;&gt;8. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B071WJWSRS/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=6bdddbdd52bc5ad19535076f27bd317b&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B071WJWSRS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Hyaluronic Acid ($12.00)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well finally we come down to the holy grail skin care ingredient for dry skin. Hyaluronic Acid is one of the best ingredient for dry skin and my personal favourite is the one from the ordinary. Now, what we need to understand yet again is that Hyaluronic Acid is not a moisturizing ingredient rather it is an hydrating ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our body naturally produces it but with age the amount of natural HA decrease in our body and that is why we need to apply it topically. This product is also formulated with Vitamin B5 which also enhances the surface of the hydration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find many products in the market these days which claims to have HA in them. However, HA is too large molecule to penetrate the skin and instead stays on the top of the skin. This is why our skin feels smooth and soft after the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ordinary-hyaluronic-acid.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The Ordinary Hyaluronic Acid &quot; title=&quot;The Ordinary Hyaluronic Acid &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-cerave-100-mineral-sunscreen-spf-50-1399&quot;&gt;9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KLY4RYG/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=eb51c37ebcb88abe714387579515625e&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07KLY4RYG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50 ($13.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mineral-based sunscreen, also known as a physical sunscreen, reflects UVA/UVB rays to protect the skin. It contains three essential ceramides that help restore the skin’s natural barrier and lock in moisture long after application. The product is oxybenzone free, oil free, paraben free, fragrance free, chemical-filter free as well as non-comodogenic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ceravemineralsunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; title=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-neutrogena-ultra-sheer-dry-touch-sunscreen-797&quot;&gt;10. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000EPA4GQ/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=ab7309e43e4d9997ee6340578126dc4d&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000EPA4GQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen ($7.97)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Neutrogen’s Sheer Dry Touch Sunscreen everyday. This sunscreen helps defend the skin against the sign of aging. Furthermore, it prevents sunburn and decreases the risk of skin cancer when used as directed. It also protects the skin from UVA &amp;amp; UVB rays &amp;amp; antioxidant complex protects it from damaging free radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product doesn’t leave any white cast and furthermore is fragnance free. The product is non-comodogenic and well less is more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well my mom also started using this under my influence and she thinks that using this sunscreen has helped to lighten pigmentation on her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/neutrogena-dry-touch-sunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen &quot; title=&quot;Neutrogena Ultra Sheer Dry-Touch Sunscreen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have dry skin and are using any other products that has worked for you then do mention them in the comment section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would want to know more dupes of expensive skin care products, I will soon come up with such collections as well. Furthermore, the links in this posts are affiliate links and I might get a certain amount of commission on any purchase through the link.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/affordable-dry-skin-products/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/affordable-dry-skin-products/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin Care Routine</category>
        
        <category>Dry Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Affordable Skin Care Products For Oily Skin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a soft corner in my heart for people with oily skin. Not because such skin type is the hardest to take care of but rather because they need to be extremely careful about what goes in their skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My bestfriend has oily skin as well. She suffers from breakouts to blotchiness, redness to flareups and what not. Since I have been recommending some products to her, which has slowly changed her skin, I thought why not share it with my readers as well. And perhaps like my friend you all might as well have a misconception. The biggest one being, you need to spend a fortune in order to take care of your skin. But this is also a hoax like the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of any skincare rookie is to achieve healthy and glowing skin. However, this might as well question the expenses you have made so far on worthless products that failed your skin. Yes, skincare products are affordable and despite what everyone else say, they are cheap. You can build a perfect and affordable skincare routine though there is no harm in spending a huge amount of money as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you are interested in finding if your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skin is oily&lt;/a&gt; or not, then you have landed in the right place. You can also read about building &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/skin-care-routine-products-oily-skin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;best skin care routine&lt;/a&gt; for oily skin and enhance your knowledge on this scope. So, let’s get on with products that generally works for oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-skincare-products-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best skincare products for oily skin.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-cerave-salicylic-acid-cleanser-1399&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00U1YCRD8/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=3767264f4116427ef2dc4cd6caa8dd1a&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00U1YCRD8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe Salicylic Acid Cleanser ($13.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extra sebum production generally cause breakouts. Breakouts or not, using salicylic acid cleanser to cleanse the face never goes wrong. It actually works great and you can use any active ingredient later on (even those which you should not be using with salicylic acid) because you are anyways washing it off. This fragrance-free cleanser contains ceramides, niacinamide and a whole bunch off good ingredients. But like any other product, you should first try and see if it works for you or not. It worked great for my friend and she too has started recommending this product to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ceravesacleanser.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CeraVe Salicylic Acid Cleanser&quot; title=&quot;CeraVe Salicylic Acid Cleanser&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00U1YCRD8&amp;asins=B00U1YCRD8&amp;linkId=3767264f4116427ef2dc4cd6caa8dd1a&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-aveeno-clear-complexion-foaming-cleanser-1399&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00006FRW9/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=c44af623c1f4ea856b5d1b2c3ad9f969&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00006FRW9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Aveeno Clear Complexion Foaming Cleanser ($13.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, aveeno’s amazing foaming cleanser is a non comedogenic cleanser with salicylic  acid. It is perfect to treat breakouts and prevent new ones. This cleanser also contains soy, which is known to even out the skin tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00006FRW9&amp;asins=B00006FRW9&amp;linkId=c44af623c1f4ea856b5d1b2c3ad9f969&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aveenocleanser.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Aveeno Clear Complexion Foaming Cleanser&quot; title=&quot;Aveeno Clear Complexion Foaming Cleanser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-simple-micellar-cleansing-water-574&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B010RAX1L2/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=1d52272cbc0d5bb9beb50fcf9456022d&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B010RAX1L2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Simple Micellar Cleansing Water ($5.74)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend often gets acne (oily skin problems). And she also does the same mistake like most of us does: not properly removing dirts and makeup from our skin. She argues with me and complains all the time that her cleanser doesn’t work properly and I am almost tired of telling her that just cleansing once is not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, a gentle amount of micellar water as a first step to cleanse before bed will help prevent acne. Once you start using it, you’ll swear by this product. Thoroghly remove makeup or any dirt your skin might have catched throughout the day and follow by your favourite cleanser to remove any remaining residue on the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B010RAX1L2&amp;asins=B010RAX1L2&amp;linkId=1d52272cbc0d5bb9beb50fcf9456022d&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/simplewater.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Simple Micellar Cleansing Water&quot; title=&quot;Simple Micellar Cleansing Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-banila-clean-it-zero-1754&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07BSV1T35/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=ba53b295b793f08672bb8aa804fef511&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07BSV1T35&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Banila Clean It Zero ($17.54)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have already mentioned about double cleansing, oil cleanser can be used instead of micellar water. This double cleansing technique was the hardest to convince my friend about. She was like “I hate oils on my face, let alone oil cleanser”. But what’s the big deal when all your doing is cleansing and then washing it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally love oil cleanser as oil dissolves any product we use on our skin, resulting a clear skin after washing off. Furthermore, Banila’s clean it zero is my favourite. It’s main ingredient are emulsifying alcohol and palm oil, and it doesn’t leave residue on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is not actually fragnance free and if you’re sensitive to fragnances, handle this product with care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07BSV1T35&amp;asins=B07BSV1T35&amp;linkId=ba53b295b793f08672bb8aa804fef511&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/banilacleanitzero.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Banila Clean It Zero&quot; title=&quot;Banila Clean It Zero&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-instanatural-vitamin-c-serum-1675&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IDWP4IA/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=11431687f883e563a60b468eaa82e757&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IDWP4IA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum ($16.75)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason I recommend this product is because I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt;  in my Vitamin C. Infact both of these ingredient are a must in anyone’s skin care routine and well when you get them both together you should click the buy now button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem acne-oily prone skin people may find with Vitamin C is that it could be slightly acidic but then Hyaluronic Acid is the perfect solution to this problem. Hyaluronic acid acts as an humectant and not as a moisturizer. Well these are two different &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/best-face-moisturizers-all-skin-types/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;types of moisturizers&lt;/a&gt; that are found in skin care products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00IDWP4IA&amp;asins=B00IDWP4IA&amp;linkId=11431687f883e563a60b468eaa82e757&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/instanaturalvitc.webp&quot; alt=&quot;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum &quot; title=&quot;InstaNatural Vitamin C Serum &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-cetaphil-pro-oil-absorbing-moisturizer-spf-30-1436&quot;&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07GDT961B/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=b541214afb9f82b9cb0e6827531f0c5f&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07GDT961B&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Pro Oil Absorbing Moisturizer SPF 30 ($14.36)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we were actually doing an amazon haul which brought us to this product. This product is non-comodogenic and has a matte finish unlike other moisturizers with SPF 30, which is perfect ratio. My friend immediately bought it and ever since that, she has not changed her moisturizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07GDT961B&amp;asins=B07GDT961B&amp;linkId=b541214afb9f82b9cb0e6827531f0c5f&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cetaphilmoisturizerspf30.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cetaphil Pro Oil Absorbing Moisturizer SPF 30 &quot; title=&quot;Cetaphil Pro Oil Absorbing Moisturizer SPF 30&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-la-roche-posay-toleriane-ultra-cream-1499&quot;&gt;7. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01N9SPQHQ/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=5191eb7e2676d7ad7d56198e652ce591&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01N9SPQHQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream ($14.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this product when my friend for Australia sent me a packaging. I asked my best friend to use this oil free moisturizer just so I could review about it and she didn’t return this product back. Infact, she keeps ordering it and is one of her favourite night moisturizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This face moisturizer provides up to 48-hour hydration  and helps restore skin’s barrier. It is also non comodogenic i.e it won’t clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is formulated with a high concentration of Prebiotic Thermal Water, Ceramide-3, Niacinamide &amp;amp; Glycerin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B01N9SPQHQ&amp;asins=B01N9SPQHQ&amp;linkId=5191eb7e2676d7ad7d56198e652ce591&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/larocheposaymoisturizer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream&quot; title=&quot;La Roche Posay Toleriane Ultra Cream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-instanatural-niacinamide-5-face-serum-1599&quot;&gt;8. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00J5N0Y4U/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=1ead0c5c470aba5ac5a25242941ec406&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00J5N0Y4U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;InstaNatural Niacinamide 5% Face Serum ($15.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide&lt;/a&gt; is a holy grail ingredient for people with oily skin. I have already mentioned products that includes niacinamide as their key ingredients. Like vitamin C, niacinamide is also an antioxidant and you might use this on night whereas vitamin C on day time. This ingredient has anti-aging properties and it’s anti-inflammatory, so it will calm redness in your skin. It also plays well with lots of other ingredients, so you don’t have to worry about how it mixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00J5N0Y4U&amp;asins=B00J5N0Y4U&amp;linkId=1ead0c5c470aba5ac5a25242941ec406&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/instanaturalvitb3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;InstaNatural Niacinamide 5% Face Serum&quot; title=&quot;InstaNatural Niacinamide 5% Face Serum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-cerave-100-mineral-sunscreen-spf-50-1399&quot;&gt;9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KLY4RYG/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=eb51c37ebcb88abe714387579515625e&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07KLY4RYG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50 ($13.99)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mineral-based sunscreen, also known as a physical sunscreen, reflects UVA/UVB rays to protect the skin. It contains three essential ceramides that help restore the skin’s natural barrier and lock in moisture long after application. The product is oxybenzone free, oil free, paraben free, fragrance free, chemical-filter free as well as non-comodogenic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07KLY4RYG&amp;asins=B07KLY4RYG&amp;linkId=eb51c37ebcb88abe714387579515625e&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;    --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ceravemineralsunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; title=&quot;CeraVe 100% Mineral Sunscreen SPF 50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-facial-sunscreen-and-antioxidants-by-olay-sun-1698&quot;&gt;10. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07GB9GV8M/ref=as_sl_pc_tf_til?tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=4497f2d7bff3354baf099031c9fbd32f&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07GB9GV8M&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Facial Sunscreen and Antioxidants by Olay Sun ($16.98)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sunscreen protects the skin from UVA &amp;amp; UVB rays &amp;amp; antioxidant complex protects it from damaging free radicals.
It also acts as a makeup primer which absorbs quickly &amp;amp; keeps makeup from smudging &amp;amp; fading. It leaves the skin looking refreshed with no greasiness or oily look. The product doesn’t leave any white cast and furthermore is fragnance free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is non-comodogenic and well less is more. My mom loves olay, and infact she swears by it. She has been using this product for a very long time and because she trust this one so much, I included this on my list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sheenycare-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07GB9GV8M&amp;asins=B07GB9GV8M&amp;linkId=4497f2d7bff3354baf099031c9fbd32f&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=00c5a1&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/olaysunscreen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Facial Sunscreen and Antioxidants by Olay Sun&quot; title=&quot;Facial Sunscreen and Antioxidants by Olay Sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well this is all for today. I will be updating as soon as I discover other budget-friendly products for other skin types as well. If you would want to know more dupes of expensive skin care products, I will soon come up with such collections as well. Furthermore, the links in this posts are affiliate links and I might get a certain amount of commission on any purchase through the link.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/affordable-oily-skin-products/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/affordable-oily-skin-products/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin Care Routine</category>
        
        <category>Oily Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Face Moisturizers For All Skin Types - Dermatologist Reccomended</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding the perfect moisturizer for your skin is not that difficult. Now that we know, how to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sheenyskincare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;determine our skin type&lt;/a&gt;, finding the right product for us gets super easy. Today we will be talking about dermatologically approved best face moisturizers for all skin types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before heading directly onto the subject matter, let’s understand what a moisturizer is and why is it so important in a skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-a-moisturizer&quot;&gt;What is a moisturizer?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A moisturizer is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/science/emulsion-chemistry&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;emulsion&lt;/a&gt; of oil, water, and other nourishing ingredients that keeps the skin moisturized, replenishes hydration, and prevents drying of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our body naturally produces a moisturizing entity called sebum. Moisturizer on the other hand is the cosmetic preparation for doing the same function the sebum does. For a healthy skin, both sebum and moisturizer are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-do-we-need-a-moisturizer&quot;&gt;Why do we need a moisturizer?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our body retains a heavy amount of water. A huge amount of water is also retained by the skin as the skin is the largest organ of our body. But, water constantly evaporates from the deeper level of the skin. This effect is also called transepidermal water loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water in the skin helps prevent the skin from drying or becoming rigid. Hence, the skin has to be able to retain the moisture. A barrier named the lipid barrier (also called moisture barrier) protects the skin from drying and prevents water loss from the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lipid barrier is found in the stratum corneum (outer layer of the skin) and consists of dead skin cells and natural fats. When we slowly start to age, the lipid barrier is not able to retain and provide proper moisture to the skin. This is why we need a moisturizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-a-moisturizer&quot;&gt;Who needs a moisturizer?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our skin naturally produces oil, enough to moisturize the skin. But we also wash and shower more often. When we over clean our face and body, we actually remove the oils naturally produced in the skin. Therefore, the skin tends to be drier. when the skin’s ability to do what it normally does is hampered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this does not mean we should not be cleaning ourselves regularly. Hygiene comes first. But yes, we need a moisturizer. We just need to make sure that we are not over-applying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we do so, the skin will become dry, sensitive, and will interfere with natural hydration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;different-types-of-moisturizers&quot;&gt;Different types of moisturizers.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically it all comes down to skin having proper hydration, which is only possible if you have enough water in the skin. In short, the “real” moisturizer is water. Moisturizing lotions are just other chemicals mixed with water which keeps the water a little long in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three basic types of moisturizers today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-humectant&quot;&gt;1. Humectant:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humectant acts like a sponge-like moisturizer that retains water. It works best when layered before an occlusive to prevent loss of water from the lower layers of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such moisturizers are best for oily, combination, and dehydrated skin types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of Humectants are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycerin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AHAs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Urea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-emollient&quot;&gt;2. Emollient:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emollients smooth the epidermis by filling in the gaps between the skin cells/flakes with lipids and oils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is best for dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of Emollients are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ceramides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cholesterol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squalene&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plant Oils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are available as lotions, creams, ointments, bath oils or soap substitutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-occlusive&quot;&gt;3. Occlusive:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occlusives coat the skin in a protective film, sealing the water from the skin. It works best when layered after a humectant to prevent loss of water from the layers of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is best for dry skin, eczema, and psoriasis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of Occlusives are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Petroleum Jelly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mineral Oils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimethicone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beeswax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occlusives are insensitive to oxidation. This is why they have replaced vegetable oils in topical medications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-a-moisturizer&quot;&gt;Benefits of using a moisturizer.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can expect the following benefits from moisturizers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-aging&quot;&gt;1. Aging:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisturizing can prevent tearing or brushing of the skin. A moisturizer works to improve the appearance of a wrinkle. Wrinkles are also a result of the lack of hydration in the skin. BY using hydrating moisturizers, you can prevent the aging of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-prevents-dullness&quot;&gt;2. Prevents Dullness:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin on our face, especially the face, ears, neck, and chest are very sensitive to environmental changes. They have frequently exposed parts of our bodies. These areas of skin also shed cells more rapidly than other parts of the body. Hence, they need proper moisture to repair itself which allows for younger skin cells to rise to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-strengthens-preventive-barrier&quot;&gt;3. Strengthens Preventive Barrier:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily moisturizing the skin can reduce the chance of developing extreme dryness or oiliness. Both extremes are harmful to the skin and cause common skin conditions like acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-primes-the-skin&quot;&gt;4. Primes the Skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using moisturize which is suitable for your skin will boost hydration in the skin, prevents flaking and dullness, and creates a protective layer of moisture that lasts all day. Hence, it primes the skin for any further damage and exposure to harmful rays and pollutions of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for dry skin.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While buying moisturizer for dry skin, one should look after the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ceramides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycerin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Urea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Antioxidants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaponics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salicylic Acid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best face moisturizers recommended by Dermatologist for dry skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B086LJQNB2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B086LJQNB2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=e6aaffd12969d60ab2fdc76c4d4de94e&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Moisturizing Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00TTD9BRC/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00TTD9BRC&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=f37c648688f5ae22b8c32b5876d1a4bb&quot;&gt;CeraVe Moisturizing Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000KU93FS/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000KU93FS&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=1f6d3f5cce4d0ee4f0359b290d57ad59&quot;&gt;Eucerin Dry Skin Replenishing Cream - 5% Urea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003QXZWYW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003QXZWYW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=89447c3f6b9e91536ebb8b94b735e649&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Lipikar Balm AP+ Intense Repair Body Cream for Extra Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for oily skin.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While buying moisturizer for oily skin, one should look after the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimethicone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycolic acid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Niacinamide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retinol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jojoba Oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grapeseed Oil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best face moisturizers recommended by Dermatologist for oily skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01N9SPQHQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01N9SPQHQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=6cf7d4e061b1206e145d3225d1be251a&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer, Oil-Free Face Cream with Niacinamide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ZE3T6MG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00ZE3T6MG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=8c440a3ddbee19feead2dded5738fe8a&quot;&gt;First Aid Beauty Skin Rescue Oil-Free Mattifying Gel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-combination-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for combination skin.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While buying moisturizer for combination skin, one should look after the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimethicone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycerin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Urea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mineral oils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best face moisturizers recommended by Dermatologist for combination skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NWGCZ2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000NWGCZ2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=0063540c9b81f9ef9b9ff7b9700c5ab8&quot;&gt;Vanicream Moisturizing Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00365DABC/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00365DABC&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=04dfbd8910cd16dae44dc4994451be9f&quot;&gt;CeraVe PM Facial Moisturizing Lotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for sensitive skin.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While buying moisturizer for sensitive skin, one should look after the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimethicone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycerin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shea Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural oils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best face moisturizers recommended by Dermatologist for sensitive skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01N9SPQHQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01N9SPQHQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=6cf7d4e061b1206e145d3225d1be251a&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer, Oil-Free Face Cream with Niacinamide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01M68AVUB/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01M68AVUB&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=0347563b287905e908b53ba00f0b96b2&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Redness Relieving Night Moisturizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-mature-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for mature skin.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While buying moisturizer for mature skin, one should look after the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retinol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vitamin C&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydroxy Acids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peptides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tea Extracts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Niacinamide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grape Seed Extracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best face moisturizers recommended by Dermatologist for mature skin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07S6CPWH4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B07S6CPWH4&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=39ffeb1bc0f974c7dba13a449cdf1aa1&quot;&gt;Cetaphil Restoring Lotion with Antioxidants for Aging Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0038COKQ2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0038COKQ2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=22895f89e03efbacbe99489453363f22&quot;&gt;La Roche-Posay Redermic C Anti-Wrinkle Vitamin C Moisturizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-for-men&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers for men.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like moisturizers is gender specific and any good moisturizer can be used by anyone. However, if you happen to be finding the right moisturizer for yourself, then you can first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;determine your skin type&lt;/a&gt; and then choose the moisturizer based on your skin concern and type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-moisturizers-with-spf&quot;&gt;Best moisturizers with SPF.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few best face moisturizers with SPF that suits all skin types are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00F97FHAW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00F97FHAW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=9bc2097bc3fc090ea7caa4175ba1d603&quot;&gt;CeraVe AM Facial Moisturizing Lotion SPF 30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JKOBA06/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00JKOBA06&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sheenycare-20&amp;amp;linkId=94a4cb8078995abe30dcfafca1f1e3e8&quot;&gt;Simple Moisturizer Light Spf15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;few-myths-on-moisturizer&quot;&gt;Few myths on moisturizer.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few bizzare myths about moisturizer you must know in order to clear your heads on how to use them properly in your skin care routine. Let’s check them out one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;myth-1-moisturizer-should-be-applied-on-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Myth 1: Moisturizer should be applied on dry skin.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisturizers should actually be applied on damp skin rather than dry skin because, the main motive of applying moisturizer is to lock hydration and prevent excess water from evaporating from the skin. That is why moisturizer is normally used after toner and serum in order to help it spread more evenly and be absorbed by the skin into deeper level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;myth-2-more-moisturizer-means-more-hydration&quot;&gt;Myth 2: More moisturizer means more hydration.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good quality moisturizers generally contains all the necessary ingredients required to heal, prevent and hydrate your skin. Even a small amount goes a long way. If your’e using too much moisturizer then chances are you are either using wrong products or over moisturizing your skin. Using too much product will sit on the top layer of the skin and might clog your pores as well. Hence, use only the required quantity necesasry to moisturize your skin for the day and night as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;myth-3-you-dont-need-sunscreen-if-moisturizer-has-spf&quot;&gt;Myth 3: You dont need sunscreen if moisturizer has SPF.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest misconception people have. You really need a good UVA protected sunscreen of SPF 30 and above. It might be okay during the winter but you need a proper protection during the summer. Infact, moisturizer with SPF and moisturizer and SPF are two differnet skin care products and should be used independently as they have their own uses and benefits over the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few of the myths that people have over moisturizers. So, if you have had believed any of it, then it’s high time to educate yourself about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, guys, thanks for sticking with me yet again. I will soon come up with other contents as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the links in this posts are affiliate links and I might get a certain amount of commission on any purchase through the link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope you like what you read.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/best-face-moisturizers-all-skin-types/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/best-face-moisturizers-all-skin-types/</guid>
        
        <category>Face</category>
        
        <category>Moisturizer</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dry Skin Care - A Complete Guide To Take Care of Dry Skin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve struggled with dry skin my entire life. Well, the problem exactly is not limited to the skin on my face. I have rough patches from head to toe, followed by Keratosis Pilaris (chicken skin) in the legs, arms, and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since people all around the world have dry skin, it isn’t a skin condition, rather a skin type. However, there are severe cases, where a skin type is considered a skin condition. They might be eczema, red and irritated skin, medically called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicinenet.com/seborrheic_dermatitis/article.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Seborrheic dermatitis&lt;/a&gt;, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These severe cases are a result of ignorance towards dry skin. So, if we start to understand our skin today and analyze what it actually needs, we might be able to avoid such skin conditions later in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s start by understanding the basics of dry skin and determine a proper self-care routine for dry skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-dry-skin&quot;&gt;What is dry skin?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three layers that make up the skin. The epidermis is the outermost layer of the skin. When we say we have dry skin, it actually means, that there is a lack of water in the outermost layer of the skin i.e. the epidermis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is medically known as Xerosis. Dry skin is not usually serious and is caused by the temperature and humidity level around you. Especially during winter, the air is quite humid inside whereas cold outside. Since the balance between the temperature is uneven, you are more prone to have dry skin in winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have dry skin, you might notice small fine flakes, cracking, and dry patches in your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-causes-dry-skin&quot;&gt;What causes dry skin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Humidity and temperature - have a profound effect on the amount of water retained within the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hot bath and showers - for a long time might result in dry skin. So does swimming frequently in chlorinated water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soaps and chemicals - are likely to strip moisture from your skin as they are formulated to remove oil and other skin conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lifestyle-remedies-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Lifestyle remedies for dry skin.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink plenty of water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not bathe daily, instead of doing it every other day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moisturize your skin daily, especially right after you take bath.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pat dry your skin after a shower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use hydrating and moisturizing soaps and body wash while showering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;types-of-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Types of Dry Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dry and Dehydrated Skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acne-Prone Dry Skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dry and Sensitive Skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dry and Aging Skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have understood the basics, let’s start understanding the routine necessary for several dry skin care types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daily-skin-care-routine-for-dry-and-dehydrated-skin&quot;&gt;Daily Skin Care Routine for Dry and Dehydrated Skin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When skin doesn’t produce a lot of oil as well as does not retain enough moisture, then such skin is dry and dehydrated skin. The skin is extremely flaky, tight and appearance of fine lines and wrinkles are more visible. Water-based products help retain moisture in the skin. Also, drink plenty of water to supply water in the epidermis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;morning-routine&quot;&gt;Morning Routine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Always start your morning routine by removing all the dirt and grease build up on the skin overnight. Use a gentle scrub or a cleanser. You can either let your skin dry itself or pat dry it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moisturize:&lt;/strong&gt; People with dry and dehydrated skin should be using a rich hydrating formula that suits the skin type well. Start with a small amount and apply it in circular motions. Keep adding a small amount until it is completely absorbed by the skin. Your skin should not feel oily or greasy after applying the moisturizer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eye Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; The area around our eyes do not produce any natural oil. In fact, it is the area that is more problematic for people with dry and dehydrated skin types. Hence, a good eye balm or cream can help stimulate the area around the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunscreen and Makeup:&lt;/strong&gt; Cosmetics are always the last step of any skin care routine and so is for dehydrated and dry skin care. Use hydrating and moisturized SPF of 30+ UVA protection. Always wear sunscreen before makeup. Also, use hydrating and moisturizing lip balms on your chapped lips.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-care&quot;&gt;Day Care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your skin seems to be immediately dry, or slowly you seem to feel a lack of moisture then dab a few spots of moisturizer in the skin. Also, do the same thing with lip balms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;night-routine&quot;&gt;Night Routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double Cleanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Always start your night routine by removing all the dirt, make-up and grease build up on the skin during the day. Use a make-up remover first to remove the make-up and SPF. Switch to water cleanser after removing the make-up to cleanse remaining residues on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exfoliate:&lt;/strong&gt; If you experience flaky patches, you need to exfoliate as well. Choose an exfoliation product with very fine, gentle particles that won’t irritate your skin or cause any redness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydrating Serum:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have dry and dehydrated skin, a hydrating serum is a must to restore all the nourishment you have lost during the day. Take a generous amount and massage it on your skin until it is absorbed properly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure to complete your routine with proper night cream with plenty of skin repair ingredient that prevents the skin barrier as well as lost of moisture in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eye Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; Also add a good eye cream to your skin care routine to prevent any further dryness around the eyes as well as to prevent aging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daily-skin-care-routine-for-dry-and-acne-prone-skin&quot;&gt;Daily Skin Care Routine for Dry and Acne-Prone Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin with dryness and acne is tight throughout the year along with loss of elasticity. The skin is red and bumpy consistently on areas with acne and gets irritated easily. Harsh and drying products sensitizes the skin. That is why such skin requires active ingredients such as peptides to soothe the skin. Furthermore, it requires calming and brightening ingredients to deal with redness and Salicylic Acid to deep cleanse pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;morning-routine-1&quot;&gt;Morning Routine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Always start your morning routine by removing all the dirt and grease build up on the skin overnight. Alter between a gentle cleanse and exfoliating cleanser in the morning. You can either let your skin dry itself or pat dry it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serum:&lt;/strong&gt; People with dry and dehydrated skin should be using a protective formula that suits the skin type well. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vitamin C&lt;/a&gt; serum is the one people are most obsessed with. Start with a small amount and apply it in circular motions. Keep adding a small amount until it is completely absorbed by the skin. Your skin should not feel oily or greasy after applying the moisturizer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moisturize:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose a rich hydrating formula that suits the skin type well. Always buy a moisturizer with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt;. You can alter moisturizer with neuropeptides that are soothing for irritated skin and hydrating ceramides for lightweight consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunscreen and Makeup:&lt;/strong&gt; Cosmetics are always the last step of any skin care routine and so is for acne-prone and dry skin care. Use hydrating and tinted sunscreen SPF of 30+ UVA protection. Always wear sunscreen before makeup. Also, use hydrating and moisturizing lip balms on your chapped lips.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-care-1&quot;&gt;Day Care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your skin seems to be immediately dry, or slowly you seem to feel a lack of moisture then dab a few spots of moisturizer in the skin. Also, do the same thing with lip balms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;night-routine-1&quot;&gt;Night Routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double Cleanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Always start your night routine by removing all the dirt, make-up and grease build up on the skin during the day. Use an oil cleanser first to remove the make-up and SPF. Switch to benzoyl peroxide cleanser after removing the make-up to cleanse remaining residues on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatments:&lt;/strong&gt; It is important to spot treat breakouts for people of oily skin type. Normally, such treatments are drying in nature and hence should not be applied all over the face, rather than the areas where you need specifically treat. This is really important especially for people of both dry and acne-prone nature, as they have to balance the moisture in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydrating Serum:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have dry and dehydrated skin, a hydrated serum is a must to restore all the nourishment you have lost during the day. Take a generous amount and massage it on your skin until it is absorbed properly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure to complete your routine with proper night cream with plenty of skin repair ingredient that prevents the skin barrier as well as lost of moisture in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eye Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; Also add a good eye cream to your skin care routine to prevent any further dryness around the eyes as well as to prevent aging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-foods-for-dry-skin-care&quot;&gt;Best Foods For Dry Skin Care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are great foods available for people with dry skin types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whole Milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Egg Whites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avocado&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra-Virgin Olive Oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salmon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leafy Greens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olives are a few of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These foods are not only good for dry skin, but it is healthy for all other skin types as well. You become what you eat. And then, the skin is the largest organ of our body. So make sure, you eat well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have dry skin and need personal suggestions or a dry skin care regimen, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/skin-care-routine-for-dry-skin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skin care routine for dry skin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/what-is-dry-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/what-is-dry-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Dry Skin</category>
        
        <category>Body</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Build Best Skin Care Routine For Oily Skin - Morning and Evening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To have oily skin is as normal as having skin. It is not a skin condition, rather a skin type. If you are unsure about your skin type then check this out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;determine your skin type&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, you know it already when you’re skin is oily. That is because you feel greasy all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having oily skin is indeed a challenge because the possibility of skin issues is endless. You can have pores, you can have severe breakouts, acne can be your best friend and so many issues that need proper treatment and care. This is why a skin care routine for oily skin is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before that, you need to understand what oily skin is, what are its symptoms, and the possible skin types people with oily skin may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-causes-oily-skin&quot;&gt;What causes oily skin?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several factors that cause the skin to be oily. Genetics, hormones, age, stress, diet choices, using the wrong skincare products, or even the climate in which you live can result in your skin is oily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oily skin type always seems to be glowing. The reason behind this being the greasiness due to constant sebum (natural oil) production. If the production of sebum increases, the oil glands increases in size as well. Thus, the size of our pores is increased. Meanwhile, all those oil sits on the surface of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since the skin is ours, we have full power to take it under our control. And we can do it with a proper skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Routine For Oily Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin care routine for people with oily skin is made up of four easy steps. These steps will keep your skin healthy, clear, and shine-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-cleanse&quot;&gt;Step 1: Cleanse:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning:&lt;/strong&gt; Cleansing the skin is the most important step in any skin care routine. Unlike dry skin, people with oily skin types must use a proper cleanser to clean their skin in the morning. Dirt, impurities and excess oil, can build up in your skin overnight and they clog pores. Hence, a proper and gentle cleanser is must for people of oily skin type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening:&lt;/strong&gt; While cleaning once in the morning is okay for the skin, you need to double cleanse in the evening. Start by using a cleansing oil to remove any makeup or SPF and sebum of the day. Following the first step, use a gentle foam or gel cleanser to remove any traces of makeup and clean deep into your pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a cleanser for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has a gel-like texture,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;doesn’t strip natural oils, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;targets hyperpigmentation and acne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with oily skin generally use cleansers with “Salicylic Acid”. The BHA deep cleanses the pores and help clear away excess oil and dead skin cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-cleanser-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best cleanser for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Inkey List Salicylic Acid Cleanser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nolaskinsentials.com/products/papaya-burst&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nola Skin Essentials Papaya Burst Cleanser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-tone&quot;&gt;Step 2: Tone:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning:&lt;/strong&gt; Toning the skin is another important step after cleaning for people of oily skin type. Toner helps remove dirt or any residue left on the face after cleansing. It also prepares the skin for better absorption of products that need to be layered afterward. Look for a toner that contains hydrating ingredients like aloe vera, ginseng, or hyaluronic acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good toner will help balance the oiliness in the skin without drying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening:&lt;/strong&gt; The toner you choose for the evening should be more potent than the one used in AM. Potent toner helps tighten the pores as well as remove oils and dirt accumulated in the skin throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a toner for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has AHA (Glycolic Acid, Lactic Acid, etc) for topical exfoliation, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHA (Salicylic Acid) for deep exfoliation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using toners with active ingredients will refine your skin’s texture and help minimize the pores. Simultaneously, it will help balance the moisture of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-toner-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best toner for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.renskincare.com/products/ready-steady-glow-daily-aha-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ren Skin Care Ready Steady Glow Daily AHA Tonic.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paulaschoice.com/skin-perfecting-2pct-bha-liquid-exfoliant/201.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paula Choice 2% BHA Liquid Exfoliant.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-targeted-treatments&quot;&gt;Step 3: Targeted Treatments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step depends on what skin concern you are trying to treat. Based on that, you have to determine what serums, essence, or ampoules you need to invest in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with oily skin may have severe acne, fine lines and wrinkles, hyperpigmentation, and many more skin concerns. One of the major concerns to tackle still being balanced oil production. Moreover, even if your skin is oily, it doesn’t mean it is hydrated as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, if you feel you’re skin needs hydration, then you need to use a hydrating serum. If you want to balance oil production, you need to use an oil-based serum. Similarly, if you want to fight fine lines and wrinkles, you need to use anti-aging serums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-treatment-for-oily-skin-retinol&quot;&gt;The best treatment for oily skin: Retinol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dermatologists swears by retinol and it is by far the best treatment for oily skin. Oily skin can tolerate retinol the best. It should be applied at night and slowly introduced in your skin care routine. Start using it two or three times a week for the first month. It is a drying ingredient so go slow with this product and gradually increase the use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retinol is a powerful active ingredient that has so many purposes. From dealing with acne to dark spots, fine lines and wrinkles, retinol literally helps you age back. If you’re interested to find a single solution for your skin issues, retinol is the one you should opt for. If you’re impressed as well by this ingredient, learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenyskincare.com/retinol-in-skin-care-uses-benefits/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;how to incorporate retinol in your skin care routine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/serums/resurfacing-retinol-serum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe Resurfacing Retinol Serum.&amp;lt;/retinol&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laroche-posay.us/face-and-body-skin-care/face-products/face-serum/retinol-b3-pure-retinol-serum-3337875694469.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Retinol B3 Pure Retinol Serum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-treatment-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Other treatment for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-azelaic-acid-suspension-10pct-30ml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Azelaic Acid Suspension 10%.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/tranexamic-acid-night-treatment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Inkey List Tranexamic Acid.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-alpha-arbutin-2pct-ha-30ml?redir=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Alpha Arbutin 2% + HA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-moisturize&quot;&gt;Step 4: Moisturize:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisturizing is very crucial for people with oily skin. There is some weird myth that if you have oily skin, you don’t need to or shouldn’t moisturize, which is completely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All skin types need moisturizer, but if you have oily skin, you should be more careful with what kind of moisturizer you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a moisturizer for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is lightweight,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;free of oil,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;water-based and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;absorbs easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-moisturizer-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizer for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youthtothepeople.com/products/superfood-air-whip-moisture-cream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Youth To The People Superfood Air-Whip Moisture Cream.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghostdemocracy.com/products/clean-lightweight-daily-face-moisturizer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ghost Democracy Clean
Lightweight Daily Face Moisturizer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the four-step skin care routine you can use in the morning and evening to keep your skin healthy, clear, and grease-free. Once, you’re done with these steps, all you need to do is add an SPF as the last step of the morning skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-spf-am-only&quot;&gt;Step 5: SPF (AM Only)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final step of skin care routine for oily skin. You should always a broad spectrum SPF every day right before you apply your makeup or heading outdoors. This will help protect your skin from harmful UV rays that can prematurely age your skin. Opt for a broad-spectrum sunscreen that boasts an ultra-light, matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-spf-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best SPF for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kiehls.com/skincare/face-body-sunscreen/super-fluid-daily-uv-defense-spf-50/833.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Kiehl’s Super Fluid Daily UV Defense SPF 50+.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;weekly-skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Weekly skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-face-masks&quot;&gt;1. Face Masks:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using clay masks every day may overwhelm your skin, so we recommend to mask three times a week, alternating between soothing masks, extracting masks, purifying masks, and hydrating masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For oily skin, at least two masks a week is recommended - one soothing mask and one detoxifying mask. More specifically, clay masks as clay masks have antiseptic and astringent properties, which will help remove oil from your pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to soothe and hydrate the skin, masks with salicylic and glycolic acids that exfoliate and deep cleanse the pores are perfect for oily skin type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a mask for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it absorbs extra oil from the skin, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deep cleanses the pores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-facial-oils&quot;&gt;2. Facial Oils:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oils are powerful ingredient that can be used in skin care routine for oily skin. People with oily skin should look for oils with a smaller molecular size, like marula, squalane and jojoba oils. If the molecular structure of an oil is too big, it can’t penetrate through the top layer of the skin and may clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These oils also are light in texture and don’t make the skin greasy. A moisturizer with alpha hydroxy acid is a good choice to use along with a facial oil, if you have oily skin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other-important-factors-that-help-with-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Other important factors that help with oily skin.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-choose-the-right-products&quot;&gt;1. Choose the right products:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have oily skin, products with mineral oil, petrolatum, and alcohol-based should be avoided. Also, while choosing products, one should always choose the “non-comedogenic” ones, which would not clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil-free moisturizers work great for such skin types. Chemical exfoliators tend to be gentle and they unclog the pores, hence, minimize breakouts. Clay masks also soothe the inflammation and control the oil in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cleanse your skin twice a day rather than over-cleaning as drying out your pores can cause them to produce even more oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-manage-sleep-and-stress-level&quot;&gt;2. Manage sleep and stress level:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skin health is directly proportional to sleep and stress levels. You should always be able to find time to relax, exercise, meditate and sleep. Lack of sleep and stress causes hormonal imbalances, which will affect skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-eat-proper-diet&quot;&gt;3. Eat proper diet:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oily skin is caused by high sebum production. We can control excess sebum production by eating a diet high in antioxidants. You can include a lot of veggies and less amount of sugar and animal products in your diet. Change of diet can reduce oiliness in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>/skin-care-routine-products-oily-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/skin-care-routine-products-oily-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin Care Routine</category>
        
        <category>Oily Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
