<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sheeny Care</title>
    <description>Skin Care is made easy with Sheeny Care as we help you make skincare routines understand skincare products, talk about various skin care regimen, and give you insights on beauty products and services.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 21:33:50 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 21:33:50 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Build Best Skin Care Routine For Oily Skin - Morning and Evening.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To have oily skin is as normal as having skin. It is not a skin condition, rather a skin type. To &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;determine&lt;/a&gt; whether you have oily skin or not is super easy. In fact, you know it already when you’re skin is oily. That is because you feel greasy all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having oily skin is indeed a challenge because the possibility of skin issues is endless. You can have pores, you can have severe breakouts, acne can be your best friend and so many issues that need proper treatment and care. This is why a skin care routine for oily skin is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before that, you need to understand what oily skin is, what are its symptoms, and the possible skin types people with oily skin may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-causes-oily-skin&quot;&gt;What causes oily skin?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several factors that cause the skin to be oily. Genetics, hormones, age, stress, diet choices, using the wrong skincare products, or even the climate in which you live can result in your skin is oily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oily skin type always seems to be glowing. The reason behind this being the greasiness due to constant sebum (natural oil) production. If the production of sebum increases, the oil glands increases in size as well. Thus, the size of our pores is increased. Meanwhile, all those oil sits on the surface of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since the skin is ours, we have full power to take it under our control. And we can do it with a proper skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Routine For Oily Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning routine for people with oily skin is made up of four easy steps. These steps will keep your skin healthy, clear, and shine-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-cleanse&quot;&gt;Step 1: Cleanse:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning:&lt;/strong&gt; Cleansing the skin is the most important step in any skin care routine. Unlike dry skin, people with oily skin types must use a proper cleanser to clean their skin in the morning. Dirt, impurities and excess oil, can build up in your skin overnight and they clog pores. Hence, a proper and gentle cleanser is must for people of oily skin type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening:&lt;/strong&gt; While cleaning once in the morning is okay for the skin, you need to double cleanse in the evening. Start by using a cleansing oil to remove any makeup or SPF and sebum of the day. Following the first step, use a gentle foam or gel cleanser to remove any traces of makeup and clean deep into your pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a cleanser for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has a gel-like texture,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;doesn’t strip natural oils, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;targets hyperpigmentation and acne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with oily skin generally use cleansers with “Salicylic Acid”. The BHA deep cleanses the pores and help clear away excess oil and dead skin cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-cleanser-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best cleanser for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Inkey List Salicylic Acid Cleanser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nolaskinsentials.com/products/papaya-burst&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nola Skin Essentials Papaya Burst Cleanser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-tone&quot;&gt;Step 2: Tone:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning:&lt;/strong&gt; Toning the skin is another important step after cleaning for people of oily skin type. Toner helps remove dirt or any residue left on the face after cleansing. It also prepares the skin for better absorption of products that need to be layered afterward. Look for a toner that contains hydrating ingredients like aloe vera, ginseng, or hyaluronic acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good toner will help balance the oiliness in the skin without drying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening:&lt;/strong&gt; The toner you choose for the evening should be more potent than the one used in AM. Potent toner helps tighten the pores as well as remove oils and dirt accumulated in the skin throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a toner for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has AHA (Glycolic Acid, Lactic Acid, etc) for topical exfoliation, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHA (Salicylic Acid) for deep exfoliation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using toners with active ingredients will refine your skin’s texture and help minimize the pores. Simultaneously, it will help balance the moisture of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-toner-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best toner for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.renskincare.com/products/ready-steady-glow-daily-aha-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ren Skin Care Ready Steady Glow Daily AHA Tonic.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paulaschoice.com/skin-perfecting-2pct-bha-liquid-exfoliant/201.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paula Choice 2% BHA Liquid Exfoliant.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-targeted-treatments&quot;&gt;Step 3: Targeted Treatments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step depends on what skin concern you are trying to treat. Based on that, you have to determine what serums, essence, or ampoules you need to invest in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with oily skin may have severe acne, fine lines and wrinkles, hyperpigmentation, and many more skin concerns. One of the major concerns to tackle still being balanced oil production. Moreover, even if your skin is oily, it doesn’t mean it is hydrated as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, if you feel you’re skin needs hydration, then you need to use a hydrating serum. If you want to balance oil production, you need to use an oil-based serum. Similarly, if you want to fight fine lines and wrinkles, you need to use anti-aging serums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-treatment-for-oily-skin-retinol&quot;&gt;The best treatment for oily skin: Retinol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dermatologists swears by this treatment and it is by far the best treatment for oily skin. Oily skin can tolerate retinol the best. It should be applied at night and slowly introduced in your skin care routine. Start using it two or three times a week for the first month. It is a drying ingredient so go slow with this product and gradually increase the use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/serums/resurfacing-retinol-serum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe Resurfacing Retinol Serum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laroche-posay.us/face-and-body-skin-care/face-products/face-serum/retinol-b3-pure-retinol-serum-3337875694469.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Retinol B3 Pure Retinol Serum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-treatment-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Other treatment for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-azelaic-acid-suspension-10pct-30ml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Azelaic Acid Suspension 10%.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/tranexamic-acid-night-treatment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Inkey List Tranexamic Acid.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-alpha-arbutin-2pct-ha-30ml?redir=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Alpha Arbutin 2% + HA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-moisturize&quot;&gt;Step 4: Moisturize:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisturizing is very crucial for people with oily skin. There is some weird myth that if you have oily skin, you don’t need to or shouldn’t moisturize, which is completely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All skin types need moisturizer, but if you have oily skin, you should be more careful with what kind of moisturizer you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a moisturizer for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is lightweight,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;free of oil,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;water-based and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;absorbs easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-moisturizer-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best moisturizer for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youthtothepeople.com/products/superfood-air-whip-moisture-cream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Youth To The People Superfood Air-Whip Moisture Cream.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghostdemocracy.com/products/clean-lightweight-daily-face-moisturizer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ghost Democracy Clean
Lightweight Daily Face Moisturizer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the four-step skin care routine you can use in the morning and evening to keep your skin healthy, clear, and grease-free. Once, you’re done with these steps, all you need to do is add an SPF as the last step of the morning skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-spf-am-only&quot;&gt;Step 5: SPF (AM Only)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final step of skin care routine for oily skin. You should always a broad spectrum SPF every day right before you apply your makeup or heading outdoors. This will help protect your skin from harmful UV rays that can prematurely age your skin. Opt for a broad-spectrum sunscreen that boasts an ultra-light, matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-spf-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Best SPF for oily skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kiehls.com/skincare/face-body-sunscreen/super-fluid-daily-uv-defense-spf-50/833.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Kiehl’s Super Fluid Daily UV Defense SPF 50+.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- ## 2.1: Oily Skin with Clogged Pores and Severe Breakouts
Such skin experince the most breakout among all other skin types. An AHA/BHA pore clearing exfoliants either in clarifying toners or peels must be used to effectively unclog pores and reduce breakouts. --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;weekly-skin-care-routine-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Weekly skin care routine for oily skin.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-face-masks&quot;&gt;1. Face Masks:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using clay masks every day may overwhelm your skin, so we recommend to mask three times a week, alternating between soothing masks, extracting masks, purifying masks, and hydrating masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For oily skin, at least two masks a week is recommended - one soothing mask and one detoxifying mask. More specifically, clay masks as clay masks have antiseptic and astringent properties, which will help remove oil from your pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to soothe and hydrate the skin, masks with salicylic and glycolic acids that exfoliate and deep cleanse the pores are perfect for oily skin type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a mask for oily skin, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it absorbs extra oil from the skin, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deep cleanses the pores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-facial-oils&quot;&gt;2. Facial Oils:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oils are powerful ingredient that can be used in skin care routine for oily skin. People with oily skin should look for oils with a smaller molecular size, like marula, squalane and jojoba oils. If the molecular structure of an oil is too big, it can’t penetrate through the top layer of the skin and may clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These oils also are light in texture and don’t make the skin greasy. A moisturizer with alpha hydroxy acid is a good choice to use along with a facial oil, if you have oily skin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Oily Skin.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-choose-the-right-products&quot;&gt;1. Choose the right products:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have oily skin, products with mineral oil, petrolatum, and alcohol-based should be avoided. Also, while choosing products, one should always choose the “non-comedogenic” ones, which would not clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil-free moisturizers work great for such skin types. Chemical exfoliators tend to be gentle and they unclog the pores, hence, minimize breakouts. Clay masks also soothe the inflammation and control the oil in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cleanse your skin twice a day rather than over-cleaning as drying out your pores can cause them to produce even more oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-manage-sleep-and-stress-level&quot;&gt;2. Manage sleep and stress level:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skin health is directly proportional to sleep and stress levels. You should always be able to find time to relax, exercise, meditate and sleep. Lack of sleep and stress causes hormonal imbalances, which will affect skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-eat-proper-diet&quot;&gt;3. Eat proper diet:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oily skin is caused by high sebum production. We can control excess sebum production by eating a diet high in antioxidants. You can include a lot of veggies and less amount of sugar and animal products in your diet. Change of diet can reduce oiliness in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skin-care-routine-oily-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skin-care-routine-oily-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin Care Routine</category>
        
        <category>Oily Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Different Skin Types and How To Take Care of Them.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The most effective way of taking care of the skin is by understanding one’s skin type. Skin care is an art and science and we all can learn this art. However, one should always know one’s skin type in order to take care of it properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are various products in the market that you can benefit from, but you might as well be using the wrong products for your skin unless you understand what your skin type is and what you should be giving to your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you will be taking care of your skin as well as avoiding products that might be not suitable for your skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that, we first need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/determine-your-skin-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;determine our skin type&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, there are two easy approaches of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bare-faced-method&quot;&gt;The Bare-Faced Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bare-faced method is an easy way to determine one’s skin type. In this method, you should take a good amount of cleanser and cleanse your face for a minute. Wash off with normal water, pat your skin dry and refrain yourself from using any skin care products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 20-30 minutes, you should observe your skin. There are basically three conditions your face might be in after waiting for an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does your skin feel moisturized, shiny, and sticky without applying any products? You might have oily skin. Or, does your skin feels tight and strippy? This could be a sign of dry skin and does your skin feels oily at t-zone i.e the nose and the forehead and dry at other parts, you might have combination skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-blotting-sheet-method&quot;&gt;The Blotting Sheet Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of determining one’s skin type is by using a blotting paper. Gently pat a blotting paper throughout your face. Take the paper and hold it up on a visible amount of light to see through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the paper picked up little to no oil at all, you’re most likely to have dry skin. If the blotting paper is saturated with oil, then you’re likely to have oily skin. And if the blotting paper shows a minimal amount of oil from your nose and forehead, then you might either have normal or combination skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if you’re skin is more prone to inflamation and irritation then you’re skin is likely to be sensitive. Like other skin types, sensitive skin is also a common skin type and issue however it is not a medical condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vic-EMOivpA&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
.video-responsive{
    overflow:hidden;
    padding-bottom:56.25%;
    position:relative;
    height:0;
    margin-bottom: 5%;
}
.video-responsive iframe{
    left:0;
    top:0;
    height:100%;
    width:100%;
    position:absolute;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;different-skin-types&quot;&gt;Different Skin Types&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, we have 5 different categories. However, a single skin type need not have same skin conditions and issues. Let’s categorise all these skin conditions and talk about how to deal with them individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-normal-skin&quot;&gt;1. Normal Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normal skin type is neither too dry or too oily. It has balanced sebum production that’s why normal skin type do not experience breakouts too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blood circulation in such skin type is good and normal skin do not react bad to new products or change in weather. The skin is very firm and has minimal fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normal skin is a very good skin type however, people with such skin type may also have sensitivity, redness and aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-normal-skin-with-sensitivity-aging-and-redness&quot;&gt;1.1: Normal Skin with Sensitivity, Aging and Redness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such skin type are dry in winter whereas oily throughout summer. The skin is sensitive, therefore, it can react negatively to new products as well as change in season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type experience redness (rosacea) consistently and gentle exfoliation is a must. To soothe the redness and visible signs of aging in the skin, soothing nourishment should be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-normal-skin-with-aging&quot;&gt;1.2: Normal Skin with Aging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noraml skin type tend to be dryer when aging. Such skin type are dry and tight in winter whereas oily throughout summer. High concerntration of AHA exfoliation is required to boost cellular tunrover. Normal skin with aging requires potent antioxidant to brighten the skin complexion and prevent visible signs of aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-normal-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Normal Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A potent key for normal skin is to maintain and balance hydration level. Hence, a good hydrating serum or moisturiser is a must. Because such skin type can tolerate most ingredients, you have tons of products to choose and experience from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-oily-skin&quot;&gt;2. Oily Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oily skin type always seem to be glowing. The reason behind this being the greasiness due to constant seubum production. Oily skin is more prone to breakouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;21-oily-skin-with-clogged-pores-and-severe-breakouts&quot;&gt;2.1: Oily Skin with Clogged Pores and Severe Breakouts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such skin experince the most breakout among all other skin types. An AHA/BHA pore clearing exfoliants either in clarifying toners or peels must be used to effectively unclog pores and reduce breakouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-oily-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Oily Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have oily skin, products with mineral oil, petrolatum, and alcohol based should be avoided. Also, while choosing products, one should always choose the “non-comedogenic” ones, which would not clog pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil-free moisturizers work great for such skin types. Chemical exfoliators tend to be gentle and they unclog the pores, hence, minimize breakouts. Clay masks also soothe the inflammation and control the oil in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cleanse your skin twice a day rather than over-cleaning as drying out your pores can cause them to produce even more oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-dry-skin&quot;&gt;3. Dry Skin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dry skin type produces less sebum than normal and oily skin type. Hence, it lacks the lipids that are required to retain moisture in the skin. The skin seems flaky and the texture of the skin is rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;31-dry-and-dehydrated-skin&quot;&gt;3.1: Dry and Dehydrated Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When skin doesn’t produce lot of oil as well as do not retain enough moisture, then such skin is dry and dehydrated skin. The skin is extremely flaky, tight and appearance of fine lines and wrinkles are more visible. Water-based products help retain moisture in the skin. Also, drink plenty of water to supply water in the epidermis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;32-dry-skin-with-aging&quot;&gt;3.2: Dry Skin with Aging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin with aging is dry and tight throughout the year. Due to the lack of elasticity and glow in the skin, the skin looks tired. Hence, such skin requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active&lt;/a&gt; and energising ingredients, firmimg peptides and a high concentration of AHA exfoliants to boost cellular turnover and even the skin complextion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;33-dry-skin-with-damaged-skin&quot;&gt;3.3: Dry Skin with Damaged Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin with damaged skin is dry and tight throughout the year. The skin is damaged due to over exposure of skin to the sun and tends to have brown spots, broken capillaries and loss of elasticity. To even out the skin tones, brightening ingredients should be used and  AHA exfoliants to boost cellular turnover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;34-dry-skin-with-sensitivity-and-redness&quot;&gt;3.4: Dry Skin with Sensitivity and Redness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin with sensitivity and redness is dry and tight throughout the year along with loss of elasticity. The skin is red consistently, and gets irritated easily especially. Harsh and drying products sensitizes the skin. That is why, such skin requires active ingredients such as peptides to soothe the skin. Furthermore, it requires calming and brightening ingredients to deal with redness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-dry-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Dry Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good moisturiser with hyaluronic acid and peptides will help seal moisture in the skin. When Caring for dry skin, a product with ingredient named Squalene is a must. Squalene helps satabilize skin’s barrier and maintain moisture. Using product with sqaulene replenishes skin for soft, smooth and healthy appearances. Also, the air around the house should be moist to help seal moisture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-combination-skin&quot;&gt;4. Combination Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combination skin is skin type of both dry and oily skin. The skin is oily in the T-zone, i.e on the forehead and one the nose, whereas, it is dry in the rest of the part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;41-combination-skin-with-aging&quot;&gt;4.1: Combination Skin with Aging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydrating Antioxidants must be used in combination skin that is aging. When the skin is properly hydrated, it regulates collagen production and the aging becomes slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;42-combination-skin-with-occasional-breakouts&quot;&gt;4.2: Combination Skin with Occasional Breakouts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such skin type may get occasional breakouts along with the dryness in some areas, whereas oily in some. That is why a balanced product must be used to treat such skin condition. Products to be used should not be non-drying and also exfoliate the pores properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;43-combination-skin-with-consistent-breakouts&quot;&gt;4.3: Combination Skin with Consistent Breakouts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such skin may experience tightness, redness and irritation if drying and harsh products are used. Due to excess sebum production, the skin may have consitent breakouts and clogged pores. Hence, oil free hydration is must for such skin types and antibacterial BHA’s and soothing botanicals can be used to achive hydration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;44-combination-skin-with-sensitivity&quot;&gt;4.4: Combination Skin with Sensitivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such skin is extremely sensitive so it may appear red all the time. Heavy moisturisers may easily lead to breakouts. Soothing and calming ingredients such as pore cleaning BHA’s are best for such skin types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-combination-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Combination Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should stay away from alcohol based products and use balanced skin care products to even out the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;5. Sensitive Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensitive skin might be caused due to genetics, environmental factors or allegies. If the skin has:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Frequent rashes and bumbs,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Negative reaction to fragnance,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Patches of dry, flaky, and irritated skin, then such are the signs of sensitive skin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-for-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip For Sensitive Skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to be extremely careful of what you put on your skin and if it is made for sensitive skin or not. Since, the skin is more prone to irritaion and breakouts, your should avoid products with fragnances, alcohol or antibacterial ingredients. Always seek out for products that are calming, healing and has anti-inflammatory properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re still skeptical about your skin type, then you should consult with a dermatologist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-determine-my-skin-type/</guid>
        
        <category>Skin</category>
        
        <category>Body</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skin Buffering Retinol</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skin-buffering-retinol/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skin-buffering-retinol/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Retinol in Skin Care Routine, its Uses, Benefits and Effects.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinol in skin care is considered equivalent to the gold standard of skin care products. It was one of those ingredients that I incorporated into my skincare routine as soon as I completed my research on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that it is considered equivalent to the gold standard in skincare products tells a lot about the volume of it and the advantages it has over the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, retinol is one of the most studied skin care ingredients and today we can find several products with retinol in them such as retinol creams and retinol serums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a key ingredient that is used today to improve the skin. To be precise, retinol deals with fine lines, wrinkles, pore size, uneven skin tone, and texture. In addition, it is also proven to treat acne. It indeed is an ingredient with superpowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why I started using retinol in skin care routine. If you’re also willing to do so, I would totally recommend it but make sure you understand your skin before that and the ingredient itself aswell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-retinol&quot;&gt;What is Retinol?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retinol is a form of vitamin A (one form), a fat-soluble derivative. It is mostly found in animal foods such as whole milk, oily fish, and liver. It promotes skin cell turnover and helps your body form and maintain healthy skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, it is a type of retinoid of which there are several variations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retinoic acid&lt;/strong&gt; - It is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms/def/bioavailable&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bioavailable&lt;/a&gt; and works faster than other variations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retinol/Retinaldehyde/Esters&lt;/strong&gt; - These need to be converted by your skin into retinoic acid and hence works slower than other variations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, there are several types of retinol with a variety of percentages and ingredient subtypes. There is a weird kind of myth about retinol which says &lt;strong&gt;All retinol is the same&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, retinol is a huge family of the compound derivative of vitamin A. It goes from &lt;strong&gt;Over the Counter (OTC)&lt;/strong&gt; to prescription strength in topical and oral medication form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/retinol-types.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Different Types of Retinol |sheenycare.com &quot; title=&quot;Different Types of Retinol&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!-- ![Snail Bee high content essence ](/assets/images/Snail-essence.png &quot;Snail Bee high content essence &quot;) --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTC Retinols are mostly found in serums, eye creams, and night moisturizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve categorized several kinds of retinol, these all serve a purpose bringing down a question, &lt;strong&gt;Why should you use retinol?&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s find out the answer to the most searched query on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-retinol-do-for-your-skin&quot;&gt;What does Retinol do for your skin?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can expect big from Retinol solely because it is a gold-standard ingredient in skincare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is known to increase the collagen in the skin which alters the behavior of aged cells i.e &lt;strong&gt;with an increase in collagen in the skin cell, fine lines, and wrinkles are reduced making the skin thicker&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topical vitamin-A is the most studied anti-aging ingredient. Tretinoin was the first retinoid. In the late 1970’s it was used to treat acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers later discovered that it also &lt;strong&gt;fades actinic keratosis spots, evens pigmentation, and speeds the turnover of superficial skin cells&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, retinols &lt;strong&gt;stimulate the production of new blood vessels in the skin&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;improves the color of the skin&lt;/strong&gt;. It also helps &lt;strong&gt;fade age spots and softens rough patches of the skin&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;regulates oily skin and minimizes breakouts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you look younger and your skin looks healthy when you consistenly use this ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-retinol&quot;&gt;Who needs Retinol?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aging skin, hyperpigmented skin, acne, dark spots, clogged pores, uneven skin tone&lt;/strong&gt; and much more skin conditions might need Retinol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-retinol-safe-for-all-skin-types&quot;&gt;Is Retinol safe for all skin types?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retinol is safe for all skin types but it may cause dryness, redness, and irritation to some especially if it’s the first time using it. Therefore, if you want to use retinol in skin care routine, you should start slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;when-to-start-using-retinol&quot;&gt;When to start using Retinol?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since retinol was used to specifically treat acne in the late 1970s, so it was prescribed to young people back then as well. &lt;strong&gt;“Young people cannot use retinol” is a complete myth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, because this is a complex ingredient and further researches was done at the latter time, it completely depends on the skin condition rather than any age restriction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nonetheless, a proper way to prepare your skin if you want to start using retinol in skin care routines. In other words, if you have had a basic skincare routine of daily sunscreen and moisturizer in your teens then you can start using Retinol in your &lt;strong&gt;mid 20s&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is completely safe for men and women to use retinol in their &lt;strong&gt;early 20’s&lt;/strong&gt; to help boost collagen and reduce the signs of premature aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A general opinion by a dermatologist would insist you to incorporate a product with retinol in skin care routine at &lt;strong&gt;age 30&lt;/strong&gt; for three to four times a week. By 40’s you should use it every other night whereas people beyond 50s and 60s may incorporate it for 5 to 7 times per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-apply-retinol-for-the-best-results&quot;&gt;How to apply Retinol for the best results?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve known that Retinol is a highly beneficial &lt;a href=&quot;https://sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredient&lt;/a&gt;, it does depend on how we use it to achieve optimal benefits from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always start with products that contain low concentration (0.025) of the ingredient first and see how your skin reacts to it before moving to a higher concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how you can incorporate retinol in skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1&quot;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash your face and wait for it to be completely dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2&quot;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, apply eye cream first as areas around the eye are delicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3&quot;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, dry your face completely because slightly dampen skin might irritate the skin as it is able to absorb the product completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4&quot;&gt;Step 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once dried, you can take a pea-sized amount of the product and start at your chin, gradually to the upwards and outward motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5&quot;&gt;Step 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish with your moisturizer and always look for moisturizers with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ceramides&lt;/a&gt;. You can also choose the buffering technique, where you apply moisturizer before applying retinol to reduce its side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6&quot;&gt;Step 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always remember to use broad-spectrum sunscreen the morning after as retinol makes the skin more sensitive to the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, using vitamin C in the AM in accordance with using retinol in the PM, as they work synergetically, will help your skin look its best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Retinol in skin care starts working within &lt;strong&gt;4-12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application to treat &lt;strong&gt;acne&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;12-24 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; for fine lines and wrinkles whereas &lt;strong&gt;24 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat &lt;strong&gt;hyperpigmentation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;side-effects-of-using-retinol&quot;&gt;Side effects of using Retinol.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retinol is an extremely powerful skincare ingredient. Overuse of this ingredient might cause several skin issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also experience some when you first start to apply it. Here are some that you must know about if you are going to use retinol in skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you use it too often, your skin can redden and start peeling. But this doesn’t mean it thins the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also experience flakiness, dryness, and some breakouts when you first use retinol in skin care regimen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re &lt;strong&gt;pregnant&lt;/strong&gt;, or considering pregnancy, you should consult your obstetrician before beginning or continuing your retinol treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retinols that are orally taken such as Isotretinoin have shown harmful side effects on pregnant women, including miscarriage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-products-with-retinol-for-acne&quot;&gt;Best Products with Retinol for Acne.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.differin.com/shop/differin-gel&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Differin Adapelene Gel 0.1% Acne Treatment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.katesomerville.com/us/en/acne-products-eradikate-salicylic-acid-acne-treatment/10278.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kate Somerville EradiKate Salicylic Acid Acne Treatment
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-products-with-retinol-for-aging&quot;&gt;Best Products with Retinol for Aging.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olay.com/regenerist-retinol-24-night-facial-serum-fragrance-free&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olay Regenerist Retinol 24 Night Facial Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esteelauder.com/product/681/58250/product-catalog/skincare/perfectionist-pro/rapid-renewal-retinol-treatment&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Estée Lauder Perfectionist Pro Rapid Renewal Retinol Treatment
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-products-with-retinol-for-sensitive-skin&quot;&gt;Best Products with Retinol for Sensitive Skin.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/serums/skin-renewing-retinol-serum&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CeraVe Skin Renewing Retinol Cream Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/luna-sleeping-night-oil&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley Luna Sleeping Night Oil
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know you’re favorite skincare ingredient if you have any, and tell us why you love them so much. And if it’s Retinol, let’s discuss more on our favorite products. Shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/retinol-in-skin-care-uses-benefits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/retinol-in-skin-care-uses-benefits/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Salicylic Acid and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Salicylic Acid(SA) are a part of beta-hydroxy acid. BHA’s specifically are acne-treating ingredients. Most of the skincare product that deals with acne and breakouts contain salicylic acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is oil soluble and is known to remove dead skin cells by penetrating into the skin to reduce the sebum production .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it is a non-comedogenic ingredient, it is more likely to loosen blackheads and clear pores. Also, it is not irritating to your skin as compared to benzoyl peroxide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-sa&quot;&gt;Who needs SA?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acne-prone skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oily skin with closed comodones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackheads/Whiteheads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosacea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keratosis Piliaris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milia and Ingrown Hairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-sa&quot;&gt;How to use SA?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be used by directly applying into the affected areas. It is supposed to be applied after cleansing and toning. You can apply products with SA both in the AM as well as PM. You need to avoid the areas around your eyes to prevent any casualty that can arise due to this ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is known to reduce sebum secretion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It exfoliates the skin and unclogs the pores.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It sheds dead skin cells and debris.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is an anti-inflamatory and anti-bacterial skin care ingredient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It also offers a UV protective effect therefore does not make the skin sensitive to the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Salicylic Acid starts working within &lt;strong&gt;2 to 12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat &lt;strong&gt;acne&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, this ingredient is best for oily skin with comodones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paulaschoice.com/skin-perfecting-2pct-bha-liquid-exfoliant/201.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paula Choice 2% BHA Liquid Exfoliant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/ufo-acne-treatment-face-oil&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley U.F.O.
Ultra-Clarifying Acne Treatment Face Oil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-salicylic-acid-2pct-solution-30ml?redir=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Salicylic 2% Solution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skin-care-tip-using-salicylic-acid&quot;&gt;Skin Care Tip Using Salicylic Acid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If used with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide:&lt;/a&gt; Salicylic Acid helps treat acne way sooner than you might have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-salicylic-acid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-salicylic-acid/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Vitamin C and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the skin care game, then you have likely heard about Vitamin C serums. Most of the skin care enthusiast and dermatologists recommend
the use of vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;What is Vitamin C?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C, also known as ascorbic acid and ascorbate, is a vitamin found in various foods and sold as a dietary supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a vital molecule for skin health. It is an essential nutrient found in high levels in both the dermis &amp;amp; epidermis. However, it depletes as we age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-we-get-vitamin-c-from-foods&quot;&gt;How do we get Vitamin C from foods?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several good sources of vitamin C in foods. We get vitamin C from several foods such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citrus fruits like Oranges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strawberry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackcurrants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brussels sprouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potatoes etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we’re probably getting Vitamin C from our diet we do not know whether it does go into our skin or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;forms-of-vitamin-c-in-skin-care&quot;&gt;Forms of Vitamin C in Skin Care&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-ascorbic acid is the purest and potent form of Vitamin C. It is one of the most important and commonly used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredient&lt;/a&gt; as it has a huge role in collagen synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other less potent derivatives of L-ascorbic acid are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sodium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Palmitate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ascorbyl Glucoside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-O Ethyl Ascorbic Acid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all the forms of Vitamin C have antioxidants, there are few formulas of vitamin C that works better than the other in skin care.
As said earlier, Ascorbic Acid, also known as the L-Ascorbic acid is the most studied form of vitamin C. When this formula is properly created below the pH level of 4(2.6 - 3.2) which is the ideal range, it helps create younger looking, firmir skin while fading dark spots, pigmentations and signs of uneven skin tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are studies of Vitamin C with higher concerntration of upto 30% and have been used in the study of animal, maximum absorbtion was found with a 20% Vitamin C solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve known that Vitamin C is a highly beneficial antioxidant ingredient, it has plenty of other properties that helps both the skin and the body and deserves a permanent place in your skin care cabinets. Lets talk in depth about all the goodness of Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-it-suits-all-skin-type&quot;&gt;1. It suits all skin type:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is known to improve several skin issues but it is not limited to a skin type. Most people can easily use topical Vitamin C for a prolonged period of time, without having faced any reactions on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with hypersensitive skin may experience irritation but perhaps this occurs in rare cases only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-it-hydrates-the-skin&quot;&gt;2. It hydrates the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our skin is not properly hydrated in most of the cases. The reason behind this is very simple, we are top to bottom covered by the skin. Comprising 64% of water, your skin needs hydration.
Hence, one of the main vitamin C derivatives used in skin care called Magnesium ascorbyl phosphate, has been shown to help the skin retain water and prevent it from being too dry(dehydrated) or oily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-it-brightens-the-skin&quot;&gt;3. It brightens the skin:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C helps fade pigmentation and reduce dullness of the skin, giving the skin a even tone and youthful glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-it-helps-lighten-pigmentation&quot;&gt;4. It helps lighten pigmentation:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperpigmentaion (sun-spots, age-spots and melasma) occurs when an enzyme called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/what-is-melanin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;melanin&lt;/a&gt; is over produced in the skin. Hypepigmentaion can also occured in areas where acne has healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C has shown to reduce the production of melanin in the skin and help fade dark spots leading to an even tone skin complexion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5-it-promotes-collagen-production&quot;&gt;5. It promotes collagen production:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collagen is a naturally occuring protein that depletes over time. Vitamin C is well known for boosting collagen production in the skin. Lower level of collagen leads to fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase in collagen production has multiple advantages to the skin. This protein helps give skin that tight and plump look. Regular use of Vitamin C will slow down skin aging as it keeps producing enough collagen in the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-it-lessens-the-appearance-of-fine-lines-and-wrinkles&quot;&gt;6. It lessens the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C protects the skin against any damages and help skin to regenerate. With additional hydration benefits and collagen stimulation, our skin neutralizes free radicals. Thus, lessening the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7-it-revitalizes-sun-damaged-skin&quot;&gt;7. It revitalizes sun damaged skin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over exposure of the skin to the sun has an adverse effect itself. We can observe skin issues such as flakiness, discolored patches (sunspots), rough areas, rosacea, etc. The damages by the sun are due to a molecule called free radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are atoms but with missing elctrones. Hence, on their serach of electon, they steat it from our skin, causing a significant damage to the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Vitamin C is rich in antioxidant and they protect the skin cells by giving an electron to these radicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;8-it-helps-soothe-sunburns&quot;&gt;8. It helps soothe sunburns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of sunscreen is doubled when Vitamin C is layered underneath it. Hence, Vitamin C aids in calming the skin and increasing the cell turnover. Hence, the sunburnt skin is rejuvenated faster i.e it replaces the damaged cells with healthy new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Who needs Vitamin C Serum?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skin types&lt;/strong&gt; need Vitamin C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C can be used both in the AM and PM after cleansing the skin. Furthermore, it can also be layered with acids and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;niacinamide&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it can be irritating if used in a high percentage. Hence, if you are new to this ingredient, opt for a less potent derivative or lower percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stability-of-vitamin-c-serum&quot;&gt;Stability of Vitamin C Serum.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stability of this ingredient depends on its formulation, preservatives used, and encapsulation. The reason behind this is because ascorbic acid easily oxidizes to dehydroascorbic acid when exposed to oxygen &amp;amp; light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily determine whether the product you have has oxidized or not by checking its color. If the color of the serum tends to be brown or orange from colorless, then it probably has been oxidized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxidized vitamin c is likely to be less effective to the skin. In other words, formulas with water are stabilized using Ferulic Acid and Vitamin E to slow down the oxidization process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Vitamin C starts working within &lt;strong&gt;6 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat &lt;strong&gt;hyperpigmentation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;hydrate the skin&lt;/strong&gt; whereas &lt;strong&gt;12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat &lt;strong&gt;fine lines and wrinkles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-products-with-vitamin-c&quot;&gt;Best Products with Vitamin C.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indeedlabs.com/shop/vitamin-c24-s/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Indeed Labs Vitamin C24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sundayriley.com/products/ceo-vitamin-c-brightening-serum&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunday Riley C.E.O 15% Vitamin C Brightening Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-magnesium-ascorbyl-phosphate-10pct-30ml?redir=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Ordinary Magnesium Ascorbyl Phosphate 10%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know you’re favourite serum if you have any and tell us why you love them so much. And if it’s Vitamin C, let’s discuss more on our favorite serum. Shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/vitamin-c-benefits-for-skin/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Niacinamide in Skin Care Routine, its Uses, Benefits and Effects.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; in your skin care routine or are you yet to do that? To be honest, science doesn’t lie. A lot of research backs up these ingredients in order to safely use them in our skin care regimen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, today’s topic is using &lt;strong&gt;Niacinamide&lt;/strong&gt; in a skin care routine. How many of you have heard about this ingredient? If yes, how many of you have already started incorporating it in your skin care routine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve just heard the name, then this article will help you know all about it. And, well, if you’ve started using it, then this article will help you give insights on where you should not be going wrong with this ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-niacinamide&quot;&gt;What is Niacinamide?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide is also known as Nicotinamide. It is one of the two major forms of vitamin B3. Nicotamide is an essential water soluble vitamin i.e. it is not synthesized in our body and we need to eat it in order to receive it’s benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-vitamin-b3-an-essential-nutrient-for-the-body&quot;&gt;Why is Vitamin B3 an essential nutrient for the body?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our body needs Vitamin B3 (niacinamide) because it helps to make the necessary environment for the cells to keep functioning in our body. It helps carry out various processes such as metabolism, damage repair etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin B3 is an essential nutrient for our body and its deficiency can lead us to several disorders of the skin, kidneys and brain. Hence, to prevent the deficiency of it, there are supplements of vitamin B3 available in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot research going on about this ingredient. However, the mechanism by which Vitamin B3 works in the skin is not identified completely. You should always get a prescription from the doctor before buying supplements for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite that, Niacinamide in skin care has a lot of clinical benefits when applied topically. Nowadays, it has been a promised active ingredient to help manage acne, rosacea, pigmentation issues, and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;niacin-and-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Niacin and Niacinamide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name seems quite similar but both of them are &lt;a href=&quot;https://ww5.komen.org/BreastCancer/Niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;two different types of Vitamin B3&lt;/a&gt;. Since our body is unable to produce niacinamide on it’s own, taking niacin supplements can help the body make niacinamide. But this only happens when there is an excessive amount of niacin in the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-we-get-vitamin-b3-from-foods&quot;&gt;How do we get Vitamin B3 from foods?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several good sources of Vitamin B3 in foods. We get them from several foods such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beans and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cereal grains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we’re probably getting Vitamin B3 from our diet we do not know whether it does go into our skin or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-niacinamide-do-for-the-skin&quot;&gt;What does Niacinamide do for the skin?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, it is a form of vitamin B3. It is water soluble and unlike ceramide, our body doesn’t store it. Nevertheless, using Niacinamide in skin care has many potential to improve the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-it-stimulates-skin-barrier&quot;&gt;1. It stimulates skin barrier:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skin barrier is the outer surface of the skin. Niacinamide strengthens the skin barrier and increases its resiliency i.e. increases the ability of the skin to recover from any damages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-it-stimulates-lipid-barrier&quot;&gt;2. It stimulates lipid barrier:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Niacinamide is applied in the skin, it helps the skin grow a lipid barrier. This lipid is made up of ceramide, which in turn helps retain moisture and hydrates the skin. Hence, if you have extremely dry skin or if your skin is mature then Niacinamide is a must for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-it-increases-the-immunity-of-the-skin&quot;&gt;3. It increases the immunity of the skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide regulates keratin production. Keratin is a type of protein that keeps your skin firm and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-it-improves-the-texture-of-the-skin&quot;&gt;4. It improves the texture of the skin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The texture of the skin is automatically improved when the skin is firm, smooth and moisturised. Over time, the size of the pore is reduced. Hence, Niacinamide minimizes the visibility of pores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-it-minimizes-redness&quot;&gt;5. It minimizes redness:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your have inflammatory skin conditions, eczema, acne etc then Niacinamide helps reduce the appearance of inflammation and ease redness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-it-reduces-discoloration-and-hyperpigmentation&quot;&gt;6. It reduces discoloration and hyperpigmentation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers have found that using 5% Niacinamide daily can be helpful in lightening dark spots and minimizing pigmentation. Niacinamide has helped prevent or block the production of enzymes responsible for pigmentation. This enzyme is called melanin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-it-minimizes-the-visibility-of-fine-lines-and-wrinkles&quot;&gt;7. It minimizes the visibility of fine lines and wrinkles:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, using the same concentration of Niacinamide has also shown to prevent premature signs of aging, that specifically comes along with sun damage. This includes, reducing the visibility of fine lines and wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-it-regulates-the-oil-production&quot;&gt;8. It regulates the oil production:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with retaining moisture in the skin, Niacinamide regulates oil production. It controls the overproduction of oil in the sebaceous glands and prevents acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-it-prevents-acne&quot;&gt;9. It prevents acne:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide has anti-inflammatory properties and it helps treat skin conditions like acne. Severe acne such as papules and pustules can be treated with 4% concentration of Niacinamide. Furthermore, taking oral niacinamide supplements has been shown to reduce the inflammation caused by acne and rosacea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10-it-protects-against-sun-damage-and-oxidative-stress&quot;&gt;10. It protects against sun damage and oxidative stress:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide helps rebuild healthy skin cells. Healthy skin cells protect the skin from damages caused by ultraviolet rays, pollution and toxins in the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Who needs Niacinamide?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skin types&lt;/strong&gt; need niacinamide. Niacinamide is typically used in people with sensitive skin or other skin conditions such as eczema or rosacea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is formulated in such a way that even people with irritation or allergies from any skin care products can use it. Hence, people with following skin issues should use Niacinamide to effectively treat it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyperpigmentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensitivity and Irritation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eczema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niacinamide is safe for all skin types.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-work&quot;&gt;How long does it take to work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that Niacinamide starts working within:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; of application in the skin to treat hyperpigmentation, redness and hydrate the skin whereas,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 to 12 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to treat acne, fine lines and wrinkles and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes upto &lt;strong&gt;2 to 6 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to reduce oiliness from the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-get-started-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;How to get started with Niacinamide?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always start with products that contain low concentration (1-2%) of the ingredient first and see how your skin reacts to it before moving to a higher concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-niacinamide-in-a-skin-care-routine&quot;&gt;How to use Niacinamide in a skin care routine?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide is normally found in several creams and serums. The products with Niacinamide can be used both in the AM as well as PM. Sunlight has less effect on it’s potency but you should always layer it in the correct order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how you can incorporate Niacinamide in your skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-niacinamide-serum-after-cleansing-and-toning&quot;&gt;1. Niacinamide Serum (After cleansing and toning):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide serums should typically be applied after cleansing and toning the face like any other serums. Since serums are usually water based they are best absorbed by the skin before any moisturizer or thick oil based serums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should apply the serum evenly throughout the face and on areas with high sebum activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-niacinamide-moisturizer-at-the-end&quot;&gt;1. Niacinamide Moisturizer (At the end):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisturizer with Niacinamide should be used at the end of the skin care routine after cleansing, toning and applying serum, typically like any other moisturizer but before sunscreen and makeup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;side-effects-of-using-niacinamide-in-skin-care-routine&quot;&gt;Side effects of using Niacinamide in skin care routine.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide is an extremely powerful active ingredient used in skin care routine. But we should be very careful while choosing the product. Products with higher concentration of Niacinamide may cause skin irritation. Also, you should not used be overusing as you can experience some redness or even worse (dermatitis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Niacinamide.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/moisturizers/pm-facial-moisturizing-lotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe PM Facial Moisturizing Lotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinkeylist.com/products/niacinamide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Inkey List Niacinamide Serum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theordinary.deciem.com/product/rdn-niacinamide-10pct-zinc-1pct-30ml?ccvis=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ordinary Niacinamide 10% + Zinc 1%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;combining-with-other-ingredients&quot;&gt;Combining with other ingredients.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide can be used with other ingredients for optimal benefits. Some research shows that Niacinamide works well with Zinc, Folic Acid and Copper to treat acne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas, combining Niacinamide with Hyaluronic Acid helps better absorption of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-can-you-not-mix-with-niacinamide&quot;&gt;What can you not mix with Niacinamide?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C is one ingredient that’s not compatible with niacinamide. Both of them are a common antioxidant. They are used in a variety of skincare products, but they should not be used one right after the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they are used together their potency is significantly decreased.  The only way to use them together in a skin care routine is by spacing at least 10 minutes between each serum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-it-the-talk-of-the-town&quot;&gt;Why is it the talk of the town?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common skin issues people have to face are acne,rosacea, pigmentation, fine lines and wrinkles. There are many active ingredients that target such skin issues. However, Niacinamide is claimed to be the &lt;strong&gt;“active ingredient”&lt;/strong&gt; that targets all the skin issues at once and treat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the studies about it have been carried out at concentrations of 5% or below. And yes, it can do everything it’s purported to: improve hyperpigmentation, fortify barrier function, normalize sebum production etc. However, we need to realize that niacinamide, and a whole host of other “actives” can do more harm than good when overused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tips-for-using-niacinamide-in-skin-care&quot;&gt;Tips for using Niacinamide in skin care!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niacinamide is known as a miracle drug. But, when you use niacinamide in skin care routine, you need to be careful about over using it. Also, you have to understand your skin and the issues you have before applying niacinamide to treat them. Because not all inflammation are acne and not all redness is rosacea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know, how you use Niacinamide in skin care routine and tell us how has it has changed your skin and you’re lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-niacinamide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-niacinamide/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are Ceramides and How Do They Work In Skin Care Routines?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ceramides are a skin barrier or protective layer that is present naturally in our skin. It is a part of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;hs=wcf&amp;amp;channel=fs&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk01vOXP40qPHjQ8BGTlRU17Llbb6Cg%3A1600836946253&amp;amp;ei=UtVqX_6LD82a4-EPqcqh2Ao&amp;amp;q=lipid+matrix&amp;amp;oq=lipid+matrix&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzICCAAyAggAMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjIGCAAQFhAeMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjIGCAAQFhAeMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjoECAAQRzoECAAQQzoFCC4QsQM6BQgAELEDOggIABCxAxCDAToECCMQJzoECC4QJzoCCC46BQgAEJECOgQIABAKUIalxgFY1rTGAWCUt8YBaABwAngAgAGLAogBjBWSAQQyLTEymAEAoAEBqgEHZ3dzLXdpesgBCMABAQ&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwj-_Jisvv7rAhVNzTgGHSllCKsQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lipid matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of our skin. Without the proper ratio of ceramides in our skin, it could result in dryness, itching and irritation. Therefore, compromising the skin barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, Ceramides are lipids that help form the skin’s barrier and help skin retain moisture. Ceramides also help the skin protect against environmental hazards like irritants and pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-it&quot;&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceramide naturally makes 50% of your skin. It is a long chain of lipids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you came across the word &lt;strong&gt;“lipid matrix”&lt;/strong&gt; in the article, let me tell you what it is. Ceramides forms lipid matrix in the skin.. This matrix is very flexible and creates a waterproof barrier in the skin i.e. it keeps the irritants our and water inside of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-needs-it&quot;&gt;Who needs it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two skin types that need it the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/dry-skin-causes-and-treatment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dry Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensitive Skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceramide are one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; that is used to treat dry and sensitive skin. Hence, this ingredient is found in barrier repair creams and moisturisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-ceramides&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Ceramides.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basically, cereamides are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?channel=fs&amp;amp;client=ubuntu&amp;amp;q=emollient&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;emollient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, it hydrates the skin by forming a protective barrier, which reduces the water loss from the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It repairs the skin barrier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It makes the skin soft and sheeny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It helps improve the texture of the skin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;it has no SIDE EFFECTS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommended-products-with-ceramides&quot;&gt;Recommended Products with Ceramides.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/moisturizers/pm-facial-moisturizing-lotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CeraVe PM Facial Moisturizing Lotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firstaidbeauty.com/skin-care-products/moisturizers/ultra-repair-cream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;First Aid Beauty Ultra Repair Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laroche-posay.us/face-and-body-skin-care/face-products/face-moisturizer/toleriane-double-repair-face-moisturizer-3337875545792.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;La Roche Posay Toleriane Double Repair Face Moisturizer &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-ceramide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-ceramide/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hyaluronic acid, everything you need to know, uses and skin benefits.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a skin enthusiast you must have heard or read somewhere about this magical substance named Hyaluronic Acid! Putting it simply, Hyaluronic acid is the key to instantly plumping fine lines and making skin look all glowy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be found in everything from serums to sheet masks, but what exactly is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some insights to Hyaluronic Acid including the right way to incorporate it into your skincare routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-hyaluronic-acid&quot;&gt;What is Hyaluronic Acid?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid (HA) is actually a sugar present naturally in our skin that holds water and helps keep it hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hyaluronic Acid within our bodies holds a thousand times its weight in water. It retains all that moisture in our skin and joints. It also prevents all that moisture from evaporating into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, right? Just like collagen and elastin, the amount of naturally-occurring hyaluronic acid in our bodies decreases as we get older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, however, ways to help stimulate the production of HA in our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balanced Diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Antioxidants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hyaluronic-acid-is-a-super-humectant&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic Acid is a Super Humectant!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid brings moisture to the surface of your skin when used in skin care products like creams and serums.
It can be used as a humectant in your skincare routine because of its ability to hold water. Hence, it continually keeps the skin moisturized throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pairing-ha-with-other-ingredients&quot;&gt;Pairing HA with other Ingredients!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid plays well with most other ingredients and is great while pairing with chemical peels, retinol, vitamins, and other acids.
The only exception would be acids with low pH levels, like glycolic acid. It may pollute the HA and make it ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;picking-up-right-ha&quot;&gt;Picking up right HA!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking the right hyaluronic acid product is really tricky. The molecule is often times too large to effectively deliver hydration deep into skin layers.
The molecule is micronized i.e. it penetrates the skin in order to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you are just putting it on top of the skin without it being helpful, obviously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-ha-injectable&quot;&gt;Is HA Injectable?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me everyone is skeptical about injecting anything on their body. With a few pricks of a needle, the gel plumps sunken areas, smooths fine lines, and decreases shadows. Then, slowly the gel dissolves over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fillers, HA is bound in a gel carrier that holds it in place where it is in use as an injection. The hyaluronic acid creates volume because it draws in water to the area, creating a filling effect. Still skeptical?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side effects&lt;/strong&gt; are minimal: you may experience some swelling or bruising that can last for two or three days. The most important thing to remember when getting any kind of filler or injectable. Please go to a trained and board-certified dermatologist or plastic surgeon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-ha-everyones-favorite&quot;&gt;Why is HA everyone’s favorite?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic acid is something our bodies already produce, it’s considered to be safe for use in all types of injectables.
Take the liquid nose job, for example, dermatologists use filler to even out bumps in the nose and improve the shape, or even to improve foot pain in patients who have lost the cushioning in their heels. It can be injected into the feet to improve the padding on the bone and decrease pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronic Acid has many benefits for your skin! For all skin types. If you want to learn about the magical stuff it does, you should definitely check-up with your near and dear Dermatologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about other&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active ingredients&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/active-ingredients-for-skin-care/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheeny Care.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/</guid>
        
        <category>Active Skin Care Ingredients</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser - Everything You Need to Know, Uses and Ingredients.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to really exfoliate with physical exfoliators…tsk tsk, I know right, I didn’t have the access to the right information like you guys do now &lt;em&gt;wink&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some research, I found out about our elixir, Salicylic Acid! Fantastically, infused in  CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser. As a result, I haven’t been turning back ever since. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salicylic Acid also improves dryness and softens the rough skin, we should really appreciate it &lt;em&gt;salutes&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product we really vouch for is by CeraVe, CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser infused with salicylic acid enhances the barrier-strengthening with the ingredients like ceramides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-should-we-use-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;Why Should We Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cerave.com/skincare/cleansers/renewing-sa-cleanser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salicylic acid exfoliates for soft, smooth skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enriched with vitamin D for antioxidant protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bye-bye, dead skin cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser provides gentle, non-irritating exfoliation without harsh micro-beads or grains that can scratch or injure the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it is suitable for the face and body as well as acne-prone and psoriasis-prone skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The salicylic acid cleanser does more than just exfoliate the skin. It softens and helps to restore the skin’s natural barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-of-the-important-ingredients-in-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;Some of the important ingredients in CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-ceramide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ceramides:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps restore and maintain the skin’s natural barrier
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/hyaluronic-acid-skin-benefits-uses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyaluronic acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps the skin retain moisture
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-niacinamide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niacinamide:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps repair a compromised skin barrier 
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheenycare.com/what-is-salicylic-acid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Salicylic Acid:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; deep cleanses the skin by penetrating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-cerave-renewing-salicylic-acid-cleanser&quot;&gt;How to CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firstly, wet skin with lukewarm water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secondly, massage the cleanser into the skin in a gentle, circular motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, rinse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser’s formula is also non-comedogenic, fragrance-free, and enriched with vitamin D for extra antioxidant protection. It effectively removes dirt, oil, and makeup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love their formula and the ingredients. As a result, the product is much loved in the beauty community. I’m going to get my bottle of CeraVe Renewing Salicylic Acid Cleanser today, when are you going?  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cerave-salicylic-acid-cleanser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cerave-salicylic-acid-cleanser/</guid>
        
        <category>Face</category>
        
        <category>Cleanser</category>
        
        <category>CeraVe</category>
        
        <category>Acne-Prone Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Skin Care</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
